<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-09T22:53:02+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/</id><title type="html">mark</title><subtitle>personal blog of Dr Mark OConnor - on writing - poetry - tech - miscellaneous</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bloodlines</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/03/09/Bloodlines.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bloodlines" /><published>2021-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/03/09/Bloodlines</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/03/09/Bloodlines.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt; We enjoy the night, the darkness, where we can do things that aren't acceptable in the light. Night is when we slake our thirst. - William Hill&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;section&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;Bloodlines&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;

As Eva left Mr Silvano’s room, she slammed the door shut. The reverberations echoed through the open-plan exterior.
    ‘Shit,’ sorry.
    She scanned the office space for her best friend, Milly. No luck. Xerox machines, water coolers and Ficus plants demarcated activity zones, all lit with a harsh neon. She had to share this news quickly. Other faces, recent dates, embarrassed faces, looked across from their workstations, like chickens stretching their necks, interrupting their corn pecking to see who had slammed a door and why.
    ‘Thumbs up or down?’ said a spotty-faced boy expectantly holding out the office mail to Eva.
    ‘What?’
    ‘Sacked? No-one slams Mr Silvano’s door like that,’ he prodded Eva gently on the arm with the mail,’ you know unless… unless they’ve been fired?’
    Eva checked the door. She caressed its gothic lettering, S-I-L-V-A-N-O, each crimson letter embossed with gold-leaf. Different from all the others, especially her office - open plan - where the not-so-important people worked. Partners had frosted glass doors and windows with their name etched onto the door. And then there was Mr Silvano - corner office, all glass and gold, gothic etching. There were rumours his office has secret exits. Rumours. Allegations. Years before Eva was there. Girls like her, now gone.
    ‘Nice, eh?’ said the mail-boy, tucking a bunch of envelopes under Eva’s arm to join one already there. ‘That’s what you get when you’re the boss.’ He disappeared into the adjacent office, and the chickens slowly returned to their roosts. Eva reassured there was no damage to the door, straightened her ruffled blouse and rubbed at a stiffness in her neck. Discarding the mail onto her desk, she held the envelope Mr Silvano had given her, weighed it in her hands, turning it over several times, inspecting every edge, corner and ink-mark. She hesitated to open it. Chicken heads were still popping up and looking over towards her. A low rumble of voices, gossiping, swapping theories, prompting others to investigate, to poke their noses where they didn’t belong. She imagined what her grandmother used to do to chickens. Spindle legs strung, hoisted, throats slit. Blood. It was the first time Eva could remember seeing blood, being touched and splashed by it. Her grandmother would laugh at her flinching.
    ‘Country ways, Eva, that’s all.’
    Warm hands on her neck, thumbs knead her muscles, fingers caress her shoulders. Relaxed. Her head, heavy, falls forward, eyes shut, but her hands grip tighter, tighter on the envelope. She struggled to remember. Was Mr Silvano laughing? Had she hugged him, made him a proposition? She had been nervous about entering his office. What could he want with her? Six months in the job. A paralegal handling straightforward probate claims. He’d been there forever. Crimson gold lettering, for goodness sake. What was she thinking? Time stood still inside his office. Then she was out. Then she needed Milly. Then she was sitting at her desk. Then she was holding an envelope that promised… promised a change, a change Mr Silvano said … what? Choose - or not choose - no strings attached. Then she was thinking of chickens, of her grandmother, of blood.
    ‘Eva? Eva? You OK, Eva?’ said Milly, who had rushed back from the restroom when the rumours flooded in. She moved close behind and gently rubbed Eva’s shoulders. She bent to whisper, close in. ‘Hey, Eva, darling, what’s up? I heard you slammed the old man’s door? Is that true? You’re the talk of the ladies’ loos.’ Milly continued to caress her. ‘Whatever, don’t worry. Do you wanna go get a coffee?’
    Eva nodded. The two women moved to the ground floor coffee shop’s relative privacy. Eva guided Milly to a corner table well away from the other diners. Milly brought over Eva’s flat white and placed her vanilla frappuccino on the table next to a collection of muffins and cookies.
    ‘Go on then, eat up,’ said Milly, pushing the plate in front of Eva, ‘feels like double-muffin news coming.’
    Eva laughed. ‘I guess it is. She pushed the plate to the side. ‘I’m not hungry. I must have eaten earlier.’
    ‘It’s ten-fifteen, and you never eat breakfast. That reminds me, you are still on for tonight?’
    Eva pushed the brown envelope across the table. ‘Take a look at this for me.’
    Milly picked up the envelope. ‘It’s addressed to you and still sealed?’
    ‘About tonight, I’m not sure.’
    ‘You’re never sure. He’s gorgeous, and Clay’s got to know him and says he’s your sort too. Come on it’ll be fun.’
    ‘I have a sort?’
    ‘Yeah, impossibly good looking and bandy leg from his fucking horse riding in full armour.’
    ‘Ha-ha, just because I’ve got standards.’
    ‘What is this anyway?’ said Milly holding the envelope up to the light and taking a slurp of her frappuccino.
    ‘Well, if Mr Silvano is to be believed, it’s the last will and testament of a Mr Clement Ambrogio, leaving me a house and stuff.’
    Milly spurted a dollop of frappuccino over the table.
    ‘What the fuck?’ She mopped at her spittle with a napkin and grabbed a large muffin.
    ‘Stuff? Have you opened it? What does it say? Is it a client? Did Old-Man-Silvo want you to give it to the firm? There’s a law on that, I think. I’ll get Clay onto it.’ Milly continued with a barrage of questions without waiting for responses whilst texting her boyfriend, Clay, one of the firm’s junior associates. His relationship with his secretary, Milly, raised eyebrows amongst the partners. Not done. Not the right sort. Milly picked up the envelope. ‘Why haven’t you opened it? Get it open, for Christ sake.’ She pushed it back towards Eva.
    ‘I can’t, I mean it’s too … I don’t know what I mean. In the office, something happened. Time stood still. I was so lightheaded; I don’t know if I want it.’
    ‘What do you mean something happened. Did that fucker touch you?’
    ‘No, I mean, maybe … no, but I remember touching him, hugging him, inviting him to … join me …’ Eva steadied her hand and took a sip of coffee. It cloyed in her mouth, and she struggled to swallow it. She reached for a muffin but changed her mind. She had no appetite.
    Milly, with crumbs of muffin falling from her open mouth, looked straight at Eva.
    ‘You hugged Mr Silvano? You hugged the senior partner of “Silvano and Associates” in his office?’
    ‘It seemed natural… his arms were open…welcoming.’ Eva’s faced flushed, and she felt warm, satisfied, drained, the kind of feeling you get after heavy exercise, after … ‘That’s not all…’
    ‘You didn’t? Please tell me you didn’t fuck him too?’ Milly made a grab for the second muffin in anticipation of the answer. ‘You don’t fuck anybody. That guy from finance was gorgeous, and he came back “for coffee” too. Total waste. Please don’t tell me you kept your cherry for Old Father Time.’
    ‘Don’t be so crude, Milly. No, he kept mentioning a choice, inviting me to … but it’s all so confused in my head … just said a choice was coming for me…the only thing I could think was sharing it with you…but you weren’t there.’
    ‘Not like me to miss a threesome.’
    Clay had arrived. He reversed a chair and sat astride it, giving every impression he hadn’t long to stay.
    ‘We’ve got to the part where Eva is humping Silvano in the office…’
    ‘Milly! Stop it.’ Eva had grown accustomed to Milly spilling her secrets in front of Clay as the pair had spent the best part of the year trying to hook her up with dates.
    ‘Hi Clay, nothing of that sort happened. Would you mind looking at this for me.’ She handed him the envelope, ‘I don’t know why but I can’t bring myself to open it’
    Clay slit the envelope and removed a bundle of faded, yellow-edged papers held at the sides by woven treasury tags. 
    ‘You sure it’s not Noah’s ark you’ve been left?’
    Milly took Eva’s hand. ‘Don’t listen to him. Just get on with it, Clay - what does it say?’ Turning to Eva and in a low, conspiratorial voice, said, ‘What did you mean “… that’s not all”…?’
    ‘We chatted about the house, and he said I should visit, spend a night there. See what I thought of the place before deciding what to do with it.’
    Clay turned the top page over to face the two women and pointed to an address centred halfway down the page.
    ‘The house? Did he say it was this “house”? Corbran Castle, in the forests of Hoia-Baciu?’
    ‘Yes, I think that’s the one.’
    ‘Jesus H Corbett,’ said Clay.
    ‘Shut up, Clay, let Eva finish.’
    ‘You mean, Lady Eva, from now on.’ Clay continued to murmur a series of low volume expletives as he flicked through the documents.
    ‘Stop teasing, Clay. Go on, Eva,’ urged Milly.
    ‘I asked him to come with me. Come away for a weekend to the house with me.’
    ‘What! He’s at least three times your age!’
    ‘Milly, don’t be silly. It was while we … close …hugging…, it felt right, normal. Anyway, he’s married.’
    ‘Hugging? I still can’t believe you were hugging him. If you’ve come into a bit of dosh, don’t let him trick you into giving it to the firm just because this ‘Ambrosia’ chap was his client.’
    ‘Mr Clement Ambrogio,’ said Eva and Clay simultaneously.
    Clay repeated the name slowly. ‘Ambrogio, it rings a bell with me for sure. I think the family were among the first clients the firm ever had. Got it going, so to speak.’
    ‘Why would he leave anything to Eva?’
    ‘Have they got any alcohol here?’ said Clay nodding towards the counter. ‘Milly, go and get a bottle of wine or Champagne if they have it.’
    ‘You tell us what you’ve found first. It’s the middle of the morning.’
    ‘Well, it’s a bit odd, but it’s all in order. This Clement fellow is the last of the line and seems he took a shine to Eva.’
    ‘But I’ve never met him.’
    ‘I think you must have. Do you remember working on the probate files of Mrs McBride? Breda McBride?’
    ‘Breda McBride? Nice old duck. She left everything to her son.’
    ’ Seems like our Mr Clement was there at your visit.’
    ‘There was an old man with her. I had to check it wasn’t her husband. I remember them laughing together. We had tea. She asked about my husband, boyfriends and …’
    ‘Short conversation then,’ said Milly, high-fiving Clay.
    ‘…Yes, the old man … I remember now … nice man. Acted as a second witness for the will’
    ‘When was that?’ enquired Clay tapping on his calculator app.
    ‘Must have been before Christmas just gone. Yes, Christmas. The tree in her hallway had fallen and I rehung the tinsel and decorations for her.’
    ‘Well this will was changed in your favour on Boxing Day last year, signed  by our own Mr Silvano as the sole witness.’
    ‘Just one witness? Is that allowed?’ asked Milly.
    Once again, in unison from Clay and Eva, ‘Yes.’
    ‘The castle, a few thousand pounds in government money orders, and a little less in some stocks. I don’t have all the details here, but the framework is sound. Eva, you’ve hit the jackpot.’
    ‘Hang on, hold the champers’ said Milly inspecting the sheet that Clay had passed over, ‘I mean, a few grand is no mean gift but it’s not life-changing. This house might be a right old money pit too, and besides, where the hell is it …’
    Clay placed his phone on the table and turned it around so that the girls could see the screen. He reached out to grip an arm of each woman. ‘Milly, it’s a few thousand pounds of money orders issued in 1680. Take a look at my phone.’
    Eva picked up Clay’s phone and saw a string of numbers across the whole width of its screen. 
    ‘Clay what do these numbers mean?’
    That in today’s money, you are worth an estimated seven million pounds and the owner of a forty-bedroomed castle in one of the remotest beauty spots in the world.’
    ‘Where?’ said Eva.
    ‘What? Who cares?’ Milly had started to dance a little jig around the table. ‘Didn’t you hear the bit about the seven million?
    ‘It’s in the Hoia-Baciu forest, Romania’
    ‘Stop dancing, Milly. You look ridiculous.’
    ‘I’m going to get that champagne. Clay, triple check those documents. Eva munch on that muffin. You need your wits about you.’ Milly jigged off to the counter, and Eva could see the waitress pointing her towards the outside, and then she was gone.
    ‘Clay, are you sure?’
    ‘Yes, Eva. You are rich beyond the wildest of imaginations. The estate has no tax to pay here or in Romania. Looks like this Clement guy has been well advised by old Silvano.’
    ‘I’ve got some holiday coming up. Would you and Milly like to come to see the house.’
    ‘The castle.’ Clay paused and took hold of Eva’s hands. ‘Holiday? Eva, you don’t need to work, you don’t need to draw a salary ever again, you don’t need to do anything. You have millions.’
    Clay proceeded to take her through the papers and the references to the money orders and account details. He produced a plastic wallet from his briefcase and placed the fragile pages inside. Eva read and re-read the newer pages, the ones signed by Silvano just a few months before. There were phrases about her scattered throughout the dense legalese prose … ‘gentle and pure…’, ‘… honest … shining integrity … honour to the firm and her family …’ It was gushing, and Eva blushed as Clay delivered the lines to her. Clay wiped a small bead of sweat that had gathered at the tip of his nose and swept back a flop of blonde fringe that periodically obscured his vision. He was overweight and ill-fitted in his cheap brown suit. 
    ‘Can I ask a favour, Eva?’
    ’ No,’ said Eva, ‘there’s no need for that. You two are my best friends. We can all be millionaires together.’
    ‘No, I don’t want money… well maybe … but that isn’t what I want to ask you.’
    ‘If it’s about tonight, then I’m definitely cancelling.’
    Clay shook his head.
    ‘Hang on, Milly’s back…what the hell is that?’
    Milly plonked a bottle onto the table and waved her hand at the waitress to bring some glasses over. 
    ‘It’s a double magnum. Three hundred quid.’
    ‘Milly!’
    Eva stood and attempted to remove the foil covering. ‘I was just saying to Clay that you two must share all this with me. I wouldn’t have …’
    ’ No, Eva,’ said Clay, now standing to face Eva. ‘Eva, will you instruct me to be your lawyer? To act for you in all your personal matters and especially concerning this matter?’
    ‘Sit down, you big lummox …’ 
    ‘Please, Eva’
    ‘Clay,’ said Milly, who was standing now as well, ‘don’t bring the mood down. We’re going to party. All that lawyer stuff can wait.’
    ‘If I was your lawyer, I’d have the most important client of the firm. They’d have to make me a partner. That would get right up Silvano’s nose and the rest of those stuck up bastards who think Milly and me…’
    ‘Think what?’ said Milly.
    ‘No matter.’
    Clay’s hands joined Eva’s at the bottleneck and peeled back the leaded foil between them. The cork on the monster bottle finally yielded and flew across the room.
    ‘Ouch,’ said Clay reaching for a napkin. He had caught his finger in a sharp piece of foil, and blood trickled down into his palm. Eva took his finger and placed it into her mouth, running her tongue around the injured finger. Milly had run after the cork shouting something about good luck and wanting to place a coin in it. Several people were making their way to the table, some with glasses in hand.
    ‘Eva, what are you doing. That’s enough.’
    ‘Yes, of course.’ She released Clay’s finger from the caress of her tongue. Slowly. So strong. So alive. She could see his face again, Silvano’s face, she felt his embrace, she was back in the office, his office, now in sharper focus. He’s whispering, his grip, his warmth on her neck. Her name whispered on his warm breath, Eva, Eva … 
    ‘Eva? Eva! Help me pour some of this, will you?’ said Clay. 
    A large crowd had assembled around the table. Eva was the centre of attention, answering questions about the mystery benefactor and what her plans might entail. She was heady with the excitement of it all, but her vision was blurring and the sounds of the chattering crowd distorting into an ethereal drone. Surreal images, from which she couldn’t escape or wake from, crowded her mind. She nodded and smiled to well-wishers and moved on after brief ice-breaking chats, seeking quieter darker spots away from the crowd. Then the sounds quietened a little, and there standing before her was the dark figure of Silvano. Sharp suited, hair slicked back with distinguished greying temples. Her vision began to clear, to focus on the ground, and she took in his glossed brogues, pin-striped Oxford blue trousers, and a Hunter pocket watch swinging on a gold chain. There he stood, Mr Silvano. Smiling, waiting as if he had all the time in the world. His presence had muted the crowd, and several of the revellers were withdrawing to their offices. Clay was now by her side, and she felt for his hand again.
    ‘Eva, I see you have been enjoying your good fortune.’ Silvano’s tongue made a slow sweep of his lips.
    ‘Yes, look I’m so sorry if we …’ she squeezed Clay’s hand. 
    ‘No need to apologise, Eva. When you are ready, I have some forms for you to sign. Nothing weighty, but if you could accompany me to my office, I would be happy to assist you with the task.’
    Milly was sitting on the floor propped up against the cafe’s wall, snoring loudly, occasionally waking and slurring snippets of songs. ‘Fame, I’m going to live for…ev..ev..er, I’m gonna learn how to fly high,… fame …’
    ‘I would suggest, Mr Ducaster that lady might require more of your assistance than Eva. I see that you have cut your hand. There is blood…’
    ‘No.’ Something substantial in Clay’s support was helping her to maintain a focus. ‘No, Mr Ducaster, Clay, is my Lawyer. He is acting for me in … in … everything.’
    Eva nudged Clay in the ribs, and he stuttered, ‘Yes, right … yes ... perhaps I could suggest a meeting later today, … er… say 4pm, … in your office?’ 
    ‘Very well, if that is your wish, Eva. 4pm it is. I might add that it was very generous of you to invite my wife and me to your new property in Romania. We very much look forward to seeing the old place again.’
    A clattering of chairs briefly drew Clay and Eva’s attention away from Silvano.
    ‘High…I… I see it coming toge..eth..eth..er…’ Milly was on all fours and singing fortissimo.
    Clay hoisted Milly onto a chair, and Eva sat close by rubbing trying to keep Milly upright.
    Clay looked down at Eva and mouthed a whispered ‘thank you,’ followed by, ‘… did he say, “again”?’
    Eva and Clay both turned back to Silvano, but he had gone; vanished.
***

‘Remind me again why I’m driving a black limo while you two are pissed on champagne?’
    ‘Sorry,’ said Eva, who was snuggling for warmth against the fur coat-clad Milly on the back seats. ‘The hire firm said none of the local drivers would take the job. Something about the forests, roads leading nowhere and everywhere. I offered loads of cash too, but there is a limit.’
    ‘Yeah, ripping you off he was,’ said Milly, pouring another glass of Cabernet Sauvignon partly into her glass and partly onto her blouse. ‘Could see we were loaded and trying it on, I reckon.’ She took a gulp of wine but missed her mouth. ‘Hey watch the road, Clay!’
    ‘Go easy, Milly,’ said Eva adjusting her snuggle to avoid the spillage. ‘You’ve ruined that blouse. Looks like bloodstains all over the neckline.’
    ‘I’ve got loads, don’t worry, girlfriend…hic.’
    ‘Well, he was right about one thing,’ muttered Clay to himself, ‘this road doesn’t seem to follow the map at all.’
    They were deep inside the Hoia-Baciu forest now. Ash black trees with twisted branches and a low mist created the impression of ethereal guides pointing the way. But which way? The sky was crimson with the setting sun whose dying rays were too weak to penetrate the thick canopy of forest leaves ahead of them. With no guidance offered from the heavens, Clay clung to what little road edge he could see.
    ‘Are we there yet, dad,’ said the back-row girls in high pitched silly voices.’
    ‘I think we might be,’ said Clay bringing the car to a stop and turning all its lights off.
    ‘Why have you turned the lights off, Clay? Stop mucking about, it’s scary.’ 
    ‘I want to check something,’ said Clay. ‘Yes, look, can you see the light? Over there … I’m sure I saw a light.’ Clay opened his door, and leaning out, felt the earth. ‘Yeah, the road has turned into a kind of gravel. It must be a driveway. I think we might be here, girls.’
    A stale, dank odour floated in on the cold night breeze. Clay shut the door quickly. In the far distance, a light, flickering like a candle near its wick ending, cast weak shadows of knurled branches onto the car bonnet, moving like the hands of a shaman healer.
    ‘Yes,’ whispered Eva. ‘I know this place. We must choose … we must …’ Eva fell back into the plush leather seat, her body rigid, her eyes rolled up, matching the virginal white of her dress.
    ‘Eva? Eva, are you OK?’ Milly smoothed Eva’s hair and felt her forehead. She’s burning up, Clay, and her heart’s beating like a mariachi band. She’s having a fit or something. Turn the car on and drive to wherever that light is. Hurry!’
    ‘Fucking thing won’t start now.’ Clay repeatedly pushed the start button to no avail. Harsh mechanical sounds emanated from the engine. The car’s lights dimmed, flickered and died. ‘Shit, look at the bonnet, there’s smoke.’
    ‘You’ll have to carry her, Clay, quick.’
    Flames from the bonnet and radiator grill lit up the area around the car. 
    ‘Leave your shoes, Milly, for fuck’s sake, just get out.’ Balancing Eva over his shoulder, he gave a final yank on Milly’s arm, and Milly was out, splashed onto a muddy bank at the side of the gravel pathway.
    ‘Clay, put me down.’
    Eva’s voice, assured and calm, repeated the instruction.
    Clay, securing Eva back on her feet, said, ‘Eva, we were worried. You had a fit or something, and then the car wouldn’t start and then …’
    ‘We must go, follow.’
    The flames from the car lit up a grey serpentine path that wound around a vast slate-black lake. At the centre of the lake stood the castle. Lights were turning on in room after room, and after a few minutes, the splendour of the castle’s silhouette was on full display.
    Eva, bare-footed, started walking towards the lake. Her gait assured and sensuous.
    Milly screamed,’ Clay, there’s a snake, look there.’ Milly pointed to her left. ‘And there too. They’re everywhere.’
    Clay helped Milly to her feet. ‘Quick, we need to follow Eva. She’s just walked off.’
    They followed Eva towards the lake. Milly hobbled and cried out in pain.
    ‘Clay, you’ll have to carry me, I’ve got no shoes.’
    Clay cradled Milly and followed Eva, whose white dress gave her a ghost-like silhouette. The house lights grew closer. As they approached the lake, a rickety rope bridge came into view that led across the lake to the house. Eva had stopped, one hand on the rope and the other now beckoning Clay and Milly to hurry. A cold heavy rain was falling, and a treachery of ravens making a squawking return to their roosts high in the tree canopy broke the night’s silence. The low mist thickened to a waist-high smog and obscured the rope bridge’s central part, which now looked like it had descended into a giant witch’s cauldron.
    ‘I can’t carry you across, Milly, it’s too dangerous.’ 
    Clay put Milly down next to Eva.
    ‘Eva, your feet … your dress. Clay look.’
    Eva stepped onto the bridge, and holding tightly onto each side-rope, took her first steps across.’
    ‘Milly, what are you on about? Follow her go on.’
    ‘I can’t Clay, I can’t.’
    ‘Of course you can, look behind you.’
    A large grass snake slithered into dense reeds at the side of the bridge. Milly screamed and jumped onto the first rung of the bridge. Clay followed close behind her.
    ‘One step at a time, Milly, good girl.’
    Eva had reached the middle and was now out of sight, enveloped by the rising smog.
    ‘What did you mean, Milly, going on about her dress and feet?’
    ‘Didn’t you see? There’s not a mark on her dress. It’s as white as it was fresh off the hangar, and her feet… not a mark there either, no blood, no cuts, no nothing.’

The large mahogany doors of the house stretched upwards. They arched sideways, coming forward into a portico closing and gathering in its visitors. A bosky wisteria wound its roots and leaves over the frontage and blended with the scrubland that led to the lake. The house appeared extruded from its organic surroundings like it had been there forever.
    ‘Clay, bang on the doors, I’m freezing.’
    Eva raised her arm, stopping Clay before he got close to the door. 
    ‘He is coming. Wait.’
    ‘Who’s coming, Eva?’ Milly pressed herself closely against Clay, who wrapped his arms around her and began to vigorously rub her shoulders for warmth.
    ‘This is the house. My house.’ Eva turned away from the door and faced her shivering friends. A loud explosion across the lake was accompanied by an intense shock of light which lit up Eva’s face.
    ‘Eva, you don’t look well. You look pale,’ said Milly.
    ‘Shit,’ said Clay, turning towards the explosion. ‘There’s no chance of rescuing any of our luggage or passports now.’
    ‘We’ll take care of that tomorrow, said Eva. The doors of the house opened, and Eva was joined by a man standing close to her. His arm nestled around her shoulder until there was no space between them. The ravens were silent.
    ‘Mr Silvano? Is that you, Mr Silvano?’ said Clay, still protecting Milly with one arm, while he raised his other arm to block out the intense light coming from the hallway. As the light dimmed, there was no sign of Eva or the man. Clay and Milly entered the hallway. A grand sweep of stairs led to the tiled entrance on which they stood. Blood, unmistakable drops of blood led away towards and up the stairs. An elderly woman, holding a bundle of towels, stooped over so that her face could not be entirely seen, stood at the foot of the stairwell. She was gesturing with her hand to follow.
    ‘Clay, where’s Eva? Who’s this woman? Was that Silvano? He wasn’t supposed to get here until next weekend.’
    ‘I don’t know, but one thing seems cleared up. There must have been cuts on Eva’s feet; just look at the blood. I think we follow this old duck and find Eva upstairs.’
    Still holding tightly to each other, the pair approached the woman on the stairs. She turned her back to them and kept a fixed distance away as the group ascended. Turning right, she led them to a small oak-panelled bedroom.
    ‘You can wash in there,’ said the old lady pointing to a door in the far corner of the room. ‘The bed is old but welcoming. It has fresh sheets, and I’ll leave these towels here.’
    ‘Please,’ said Clay, where is our Friend, Eva? Who was the gentleman at the door with her?’
    ’ Sleep tonight. Time enough tomorrow for questions,’ said the old lady as she backed out towards the door. ‘Spare clothes for the lady too on the bed, compliments of the master.
    ‘Go after her, Clay.’ Milly had wrapped a towel around her shoulder and was taking stock of the room.’ We must know where Eva is.’
    Clay ran to the door and looked into the long corridor. The woman was nowhere to be seen. ‘Excuse me!’ shouted Clay, only to be met with a distant echo of his own voice.
    ‘She’s not there.’
    She must be at her pace; she only just left.’
    ‘I’m telling you she’s not there.’ Let’s wash up, and you can change into those,’ Clay pointed at the white linen dress laid out on the bed. ‘I’m going to take a lie down until you’re ready.’
    Milly, bundling all the towels into her arms, retreated to the bathroom. Clay collapsed back onto the bed, which groaned and creaked before settling and submitting to his large frame. A sharp cold draught blowing straight onto his face made him rise immediately. He followed it to a small casement window which was ajar. He tried to shut it, but the hinge wouldn’t yield. He gathered up the top sheet from the bed, stuffed it into the open window space, and returned to the bed. He noticed a small butler’s tray perched on a writing bureau set in a recess by the window. The bottles were dusty with no fingerprints, but the two cut glasses were clean. He took one and, passing over a red-wine claret jug, poured what smelt like a bourbon. Alone. Sitting and wishing he was poking ice cubes under the surface of a Jack Daniels at the swanky restaurant they had been at only the night before in London. He noted the small noises of the house settling after the exploits of the day. Another day complete and the slow hand of his life ticking another notch. He wondered how long the house has stood. Its noises seemed well-practised. She was comforting her guests, soothing them in their slumbers, saying, ‘it’s OK, I’m here, I have always been here.’ Outside, the soundscape had no competitors—a graveyard silence. A small book, propped against the bottle he had chosen, flopped flat against the tray. There was a small piece of parchment protruding from the cover. Clay picked up the book and examined the fragile paper. The calligraphy was well-formed, and the ink unfaded in contrast to the rest of the book. He could not read its title and didn’t recognise its language, but the parchment was clearly in old English. He returned to the bed to get a better light.

    ‘The future is a bat with gilded wings who darts and flits across our vision, glimpsed close but always out of sight. Never resting, he entices us to enter his void of promises and hopes. Let this house be your first-class carriage and carry you to your rest. It will comfort you. Lie back and await the glorious dusk of evening …
S., Thursday, February 29th, 1680’

S?, Silvano? That name again. It couldn’t be. He drained the whiskey and decided on another. A strong desire to lie down overcame him, though. He re-read the parchment and collapsed back into the bed. The frame creaked and groaned as before, but this time the noises didn’t settle. A mist was rising around him. A vapour poured from the bathroom. He looked for Milly. At the bathroom door stood a woman, clad in a white linen dress, the mist billowing around her feet.
    ‘Milly? Milly, help me up.’
    But she didn’t move, just observed the beached corpus of Clay as he struggled to hoist himself from the bed. Cracking sounds, the splintering of wood, created a sickening of noises beating in time with his shifting weight. Pulverising struts of wood slammed into Clay’s body, accompanied by the sinking of the bedframe into the floor. The mist swirling from the bathroom, eddying around Milly’s feet, enveloped the bed. A crimson flow of blood soaked into the bottom sheet dripped into the spaces opened up in the floorboards. Boards that were now warped, arcing downwards, fragmenting into thin shards of wood as if each were eagerly seeking his blood. Speared, skewered and spiked through, Clay’s body sundered into separate parts descended downwards into a gaping void. Silence. The mist cleared. The bed restored, crisp white sheets, and the floor now secure as solid oak. Silence. The silence of a room containing the dead and buried. Pure and Simple. The casement window no longer ajar but firmly shut. Its insulating sheet was gone and light from a dazzling eastern sun penetrating the room. Milly stepped into the shadow of the recess. At the doorway appeared the old lady. Except she looked younger, her hair gleaming, her hands outstretched. Behind her was Eva and in Eva’s shadow a man. Silvano. Eva, dressed in white linen, joined the old woman with her entreaties for Milly to join them. Milly, keeping to the shadows at the edge of the room, joined them. The light streaming through all casements windows now swept the room, lighting up the motes of dust that danced in the gentle vortex left by Milly’s departure.
    ‘Milly, it’s OK. This is Mr Silvano.’
    Silvano took a step forward and held Milly in a long embrace.
    ‘Welcome to the house, Milly. Come.’
    The bedroom door bearing a small bronze plate with crimson lettering S.I.L.V.A.N.O swung shut, and they retreated into the darkness of the corridor’s void to await the evenings to come.







&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">We enjoy the night, the darkness, where we can do things that aren't acceptable in the light. Night is when we slake our thirst. - William Hill Bloodlines</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Colonel’s Garden</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The_Colonels_Ga.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Colonel's Garden" /><published>2021-02-06T20:48:13+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-06T20:48:13+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The_Colonels_Ga</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The_Colonels_Ga.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;The Colonel's Garden&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt; Make the most of your regrets; never smother your sorrow, but tend and cherish it till it comes to have a separate and integral interest. To regret deeply is to live afresh - Thoreau&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;
The Colonel didn’t trust the bougainvillaea. ‘Devil’s roots,’ he’d mutter whenever the luxuriant growth received a compliment from his men. The beginning, pot-bound and innocent, was lost to memory. Mostly. A present to his wife from a grateful Warrant Officer, its spiny claws now gripped the south garden wall, roots buried deep under the earth. His earth.
    The garden, a terracotta tiled floor between sandy walls, was one of many formed by the barrack’s boundary wall.  The Egyptian sun baked the tiles. The fierce Arabian heat crisped the weakly fragrant climbers of neighbouring gardens, but not his. He sipped his morning Earl Grey with the rising eastern sun and inhaled soft hints of Jasmine by the northern wall. He suffered the melting temperatures of midday infused with young muscular scents of clematis and tropical Passiflora.
    Not always. In the early days, there had been many mistakes. Too little attention paid. Too little sustenance and water. Too many thoughts on other issues. Work, career, campaigns and his men. His wife’s idea in the beginning. Something for them both to achieve. To enjoy and develop together. She organised some of his men to sweat out the first border. They removed a width of tiles and by upending the small bricks formed an edge to the wall to hold in the soil. The Colonel’s wife tried to create an English garden. Still, the relentless, punishing heat ensured any slippage in the Colonel’s watering schedule meant certain death for the plants. The vibrant greens, soft pinks, and gentle yellows of plants entrusted to her care became what he called the betrayal colour, a burnished beige.
    ‘I’m so sorry,’ she would say, as she crunched the crenated leaves of the Jasmine, ‘we’ll have dinner first, and I’ll make up for it by a delicious watering tonight.’
    ‘Follow the plan,’ he would reply, ‘it is not optional. 
    With military precision, he set about tilting angles of tarpaulin shade. He established a watering pattern that perfected the climbers’ growth and an English tea-rose on the north wall. The bougainvillaea had never needed such care. Thankless. Watering would no longer be a task for his wife. He preferred using an automated timer tap-switch. It released a flow of warm water into submerged black perforated tubes for twelve minutes every hour, day and night, running in the sandy grit that passed for Egyptian soil. It was for the best. Trial and error. His attempts and mistakes. Now in perfect balance. He’d come to see the plants of the north wall, climbers and trees as a kind of family in the way that objects became sentimental by dint of time shared. He named most of them — all except the Devil’s roots.
    Two Frangipani trees guarded the back alleyway against the road. Their broadish leaves had long decussated, forming a robust bosky arch into the central garden and its delicate flowers softened the entrance. The Colonel hesitated to name the trees. Too feminine for guards, he thought. There were female soldiers now, of course. Sweet bergamot. Oud smoke. Gunsmoke. Pomegranate juice where blood should be. Where blood should not be, values rotted. He settled on Edith and Ethel. 
    ‘I like the symmetry of the initials and the equal length. Your sisters, I seem to remember.’
    ‘Yes, darling. That’s very sweet of you to think of them.’
    A distant recollection shimmered, rendered from a full palette into a blurred haze of pinks and browns by the orange glare of the damned Arabian sun. He thought a Colonel’s wife should have liked that. Pomegranate juice where blood should be. Where blood should not be, decades rotted. 
#
    ‘Not in my Regiment, Zephyr.’
    ‘Yes, Colonel,’ said Zephyr, his long-suffering housemaid, wrapping a light pashmina around his shoulders. ‘No, don’t move, Colonel. Settle yourself.’ She rubbed his shoulders and placed a soft kiss on his forehead. ‘There, that’s better. They say there will be a wind from the east tonight and a fine evening mist from the Nile.’
    He looked at the leafy tongues of the frangipani and imagined them stuck out, mocking him. He glanced at the bright titanium white of the tea-roses at his side. English roses. Such a difficult beginning, but he had seen them blossom at last and endure. His wife never saw them bloom. They had argued about that. 
    ‘Prune hard, thicken the roots. Make them hardy.’
    ‘I know darling, but I should so like to see a bloom to colour this depressing beige.’
    A firm stance needed. Prune hard. For years, they were just little more than fattening sticks in ever larger pots.
    Slowly in this way, the Colonel and his wife talked less about the garden as it became more established under his strict timetable. She devoted her time to other things and as way leads onto way, time passed.
    Zephyr tucked the pashmina into his collar. As the promised warm mist began to descend, she checked he was within the evening shade cast from the villa.
#
In the early days, the Colonel’s parties were the talk of the regiment. It wasn’t unusual for some of the men to forgo leave to attend. Of course, they were the Captain’s parties when he first took up the commission. It was generally considered that the get-togethers were responsible for a remarkable camaraderie of his men and not least his promotions.
    ‘Who’s there?’ he said creeping up behind his wife and placing his hands over her eyes.
    ‘Darling, you gave me such a start.’ She tried to swivel around for the six o’clock welcome home kiss, but his grip on her head wouldn’t allow it. ‘Captain Crazy man, unhand me this instance.’
    ‘I think you mean Major Crazy man,’ he said, at which point he released her.
    ‘Major! They made you a Major?’
    ‘Yes, and another five-year commission.’
    ‘Oh darling, that’s wonderful. Well done us.’ She jumped into his arms and wrapped her legs tightly around his waist. ‘Spin me around and around. I couldn’t be dizzier than I am now anyway.’
    ‘Well that’s no way for a Major’s wife to behave now is it?’ he said, carefully placing her down onto the cool granite kitchen surface. ‘We’ll throw a party to welcome the new men, eh?’
    ‘A party. Yes! Oh, yes, that would be splendid. We have so many memories here and so many people to say goodbye to. I’m sure we’ll have nowhere to put the presents. Do you know where the commission is? I do so hope it’s Germany. My father has a cousin in Munich, and he said the lakes are beautiful, as they are in Italy, of course. Oh, Italy. It’s just too much darling, please don’t keep me in suspense. A Major’s wife, well, I say.’
    The Major moved to the refrigerator and opened a bottle of Egyptian Stella. He used the cool condensed sweat of the bottle to soothe his pinched brow.
    ‘Here,’ he said as he made a slow turn in the humid air. ‘We’ll be here for another five years.’ He had forgotten to ask her whether she wanted a beer too. It didn’t matter much as she had gone.
#
She had received a small crimson bougainvillaea plant from one of the men, a Warrant officer, as a thank you for hosting a party for the Major’s new regiment. Despite the unholy heat, it flourished, requiring a little separate watering at first and then content with dry fine-grained sand as its only sustenance. There were days when it seemed its growth could be watched in real-time; where its delicate paper-thin flowers delivered graceful bowers and in turn formed fronds of twisted thorns. She liked its forgiving nature and asked the Warrant Officer if he could obtain another one. He did, but it was not entirely of the same shade. 
    ‘No matter. You must come and follow the plants’ progress from time to time. I’d like that.’
    ‘Thank you, Ma’am, I should like that very much too.’
    When the two plants were full-grown, they completely covered the wall. The first plant’s alizarin crimson seemed as vigorous and prolific as the Windsor red of the second. The two had grown sympathetically with each other, and it would have been an impossible task now to separate the woody bracken, leaf and flowers. The south wall was hard to approach, and some care had to be taken in walking past the triffid-like arms of the plants that bore such vicious barbs. The Colonel would sometimes enter the villa’s grounds via the back alley. On nodding to the frangipani twins, Edith and Elsie, he’d sit amongst the north wall’s small roses pots of pastel hydrangea, observing the south wall’s Faustian growth. He would try to make some pruning decisions with a pair of secateurs he kept hidden within the unused pile of bricks taken up for the borders. The branches of the bougainvillaea resisted his pruning. Not just because the girth of the stalks exceeded the arc of the secateurs or the impenetrable tangled thicket they formed at their roots, but in their vicious spikes curved like small scythes. The Colonel no longer included the bougainvillaea in his schedule. As it covered the south wall and extended its march to the west and east, the roses and climbers retreated to the north. and became the Colonel’s preferred seating area. A small iron wrought table with Arabic filigree and two matching chairs nestled within the rose clusters. Here the Colonel and his wife would sit and gaze upon the south wall and occasionally each other. The silence and serenity of the spot made it popular with both of them. They would often take the opportunity to sit there and think, alone. And so by custom and practice, they continued. He outside by the north wall and she in the kitchen, preparing for parties and the dinners that occupied their evenings entertaining the Colonel’s men.
    The parties were not without rumour. When the second promotion to Lieutenant-Colonel arrived, it came with an offer of bigger quarters and extra staff.
    ‘You love being close to your men, and so do I darling. You have your garden, which everyone loves too. It would take us years to grow anything like this again. Years. We might not manage it too. We know the plot and its needs so well now. Let’s stay here.’
    And so by custom and practice, they continued, each in their own spheres, separate orbits, until she was gone. 
#
When they first moved to the villa, Zephyr, the original and only maid benefited from the Colonel’s climb up the ranks. With each promotion, there had been more staff, and she had been promoted by the Colonel to take the lead managing them. He would often give her tips on what he called ‘man management’, and she liked it not just because it seemed to work, but it made her feel special. 
    ‘Zephyr, what are you like at sewing?’ said the Colonel appearing at Zephyr’s room on the ground floor.
    ‘Just leave your socks in the bag, Sir,’ she replied as she rose from her sofa and straightened her pinny, ‘I can do ’em tonight after supper.’
    The Colonel removed his jacket and threw it onto the sofa behind her and handed her two small epaulette badges with the word ‘Colonel’ embroidered in gold braid.
    ‘Oh my, Colonel. They made you the Colonel?’
    ‘That’s right, Zephyr, and you’ll be getting some extra help too of course. We’ll make a Field-Marshall out of you yet.’
    ‘Oh, Sir, I am so happy for you… do you think Mrs…. Do you think she will… 
    ‘Come now, Zephyr, no more talk of that.’
    Zephyr picked up the jacket and placed the epaulette badges onto her sewing basket. ‘I’ll do this straight away, Colonel.’
#
As the years passed, Zephyr oversaw the reduction in house staff and was trusted to tend the garden. The Colonel was permitted to stay in the villa after retirement. Very soon, the regiment’s men had churned enough that none of them had ever experienced being commanded by him. He left the estate seldomly now preferring his routines, overseen by Zephyr.
    ‘I’m going to see the doctor tonight, Sir,’ she said, tucking the pashmina around his neck. ‘You sit here and enjoy de smells you like, yes? She rubbed her chest and braced herself against the back of his chair, momentarily. ‘I’ve made you some of your favourite tea. I’ve put it just here.’ She guided his hand to the left and helped him curve his fingers around a small tumbler of red wine. ‘There’s some nice fresh bread here too, and some of your favourite pickles.’
    ‘Doctor? Who’s going to the Doctor. Don’t bring those quacks here… I can’t remember his name… I can’t remember…’
    The thud of Zephyrs body hitting the ground behind him reverberated through the small iron table causing the teapot to smash to the ground. The Colonel tried to rise but couldn’t.
    ‘Zephyr, get me up I want to inspect the south wall.’
    He sat in the silence and shade of the villa. Two large bougainvillaea fronds, resting on the first-floor balcony, shifted under the vibration of Zephyr’s fall tumbled forward onto the Colonel’s head. He thrashed at them as their barbs caught up in the tweed of his jacket and the weave of the pashmina. A twisted hollow of thorns pricked into his brow, causing thick streaks of blood to cloud his vision. His thrashing dragged more of the tendrils into the fray and soon a carapace of leaf, branch and flower formed around him. Hues of red, hot thick reds filled his vision.
    ‘Zephyr, I’m sinking! Zephyr, where are you.’
    With every thrashing sweep of his arms, the spiny claws of the bougainvillaea moved northwards, latching onto his jacket and dragging ever more tendrils around his head and shoulders. When the thrashing stopped, the bloody tendrils of the ‘Devil’s roots’ swayed in the victorious fragrant air of the Arabic night.

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">The Colonel's Garden Make the most of your regrets; never smother your sorrow, but tend and cherish it till it comes to have a separate and integral interest. To regret deeply is to live afresh - Thoreau</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Innocent Neighbour</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The-Innocent-Ne.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Innocent Neighbour" /><published>2021-02-06T20:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-06T20:48:00+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The-Innocent-Ne</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The-Innocent-Ne.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;The Innocent Neighbour&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;The sweet converse of an innocent mind - John Keats&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;

A removals van backed into the shared driveway of number thirty-two West Washington Street, Phoenix, briefly churning the dry Arizona dust into a small violent vortex. At number thirty, Jo Pauli, woken by the warning beeps of the reversing gear, peeped through his tattered net curtains. New neighbours. Jo looked for evidence of children. Didn’t want kids living next to him anymore. Bad memories. Too much trouble. Removal boxes, furniture and assorted bric-a-brac started to appear across his driveway. One box caught Jo’s attention. A doll’s head, rouged cheeks, pouting lips and unforgiving eyes, was poking out from the top of the box. A China-white face once, but now a kind of faded yellow ochre, it faced towards Jo’s window and looked straight at him. 
    ‘Don’t you look at me like that. I ain’t done nothing to you.’ Jo raised his middle finger to the doll, ‘If I were you, little miss, I’d jump out and run back to where you came from.’
    His words echoed from the walls of his sparsely furnished living room. He returned to sit opposite the television. It hadn’t worked for a while, but he liked to look at it all the same. To his right on the wall, hung a framed photograph of his daughter, Mary-Lou. Faded by the morning sun, she looked down on him with an eternally fixed smile. He couldn’t remember the exact date the picture was taken, or where, or when he had last seen that smile. He knew the sun would destroy it at some point, but some things, deep, unspoken, are best left undisturbed.
He drops, onto a twisted oak console table by the porch door, a letter to Mary-Lou, with twenty dollars inside for Sophie, the granddaughter he will never be allowed to see. Draining a glass of Old Crow whiskey, to remove the taste of the envelope gum, he wipes his mouth and dries his hand on the ragged growth of his beard. 
‘So, now you can’t get to the post box because of a doll. It isn’t even a real little girl, you shmuck.’ Jo Pauli poured himself another shot of whiskey, raised the glass in mock salute to the doll, and left the envelope where it lay.
***
Over the following months, Jo caught glimpses of the transformation of the next-door property from the porch window. He never sat out on the porch anymore, unsure of whether the rotted beams would take his weight. Anyway, he preferred to avoid the taunts of the local kids. On Thursdays, the boy from the corner store would deliver groceries, and do odd jobs around the house; fix a broken window, change a light bulb, bring him discounted whiskey. He was never up in time to see the new folks going to work, or their kids on the school run. The ends of most days were hazy for Jo, and most days he just slept where he lay. He would ask the grocery boy to get a new battery for the clock, and maybe a fuse for the television. Maybe not. The envelope lay still on the consort table.
***
Jo woke to the sound of laughter.
    ‘Mary-Lou? Is that you?’
    More laughter and muffled voices from outside. A young girl’s voice, clearer now but not loud enough to make out the words clearly. Mary-Lou and Sophie come to visit? There was no time to tidy, shave, or dress properly. How long had they been at the door? She’d come to apologise? No, he would show her the envelope, she would read his words, and he would give Sophie the money directly. Jo struggled to his feet and swept several empty beer bottles and glasses under the sofa. He tucked his stained shirt tails into the loose waistband of his jeans and swept back two greasy fops of grey hair behind his ears, licking his fingers, pressing them into place.
    By the time he got to the front door the laughing had stopped. He could still hear stifled giggles on the other side of the door, the high-pitched joyous sounds of the innocent. He imagined what Sophie would look like. How Mary-Lou might have changed. How old would she be now? How old was Sophie? How old was he now? He caught his reflection in the blank television screen. He’d looked at it for too long. He picked up the envelope. Twenty dollars. She would be pleased. He opened the door and looked down into the face of a small girl he had never seen before, and he held out the envelope.
     ‘Sophie, my beautiful girl. This is for you,’ said Jo, placing the envelope into the girl’s hand. ‘Where is your Mummy? Where’s my Mary-Lou?’
    ‘Can I have my ball back? Please mister.’
    ‘Kiss me, darling, hug me, please.’
    Jo bent down and stumbled as he did so. He grabbed at the girl’s hand to regain his balance but missed, tumbled to the floor and caught her cheek with the corner of the envelope, drawing a small string of blood.
 ‘Fuck it,’ said Jo, rubbing his knee. 
     The girl disappeared. The road outside was busy, and a thick haze of dust hung in the air. Jo picked himself up and hobbled a few steps onto the front porch. 
 ‘Sophie, my darling, please come back.’
 He could hear voices, carried on a warm breeze, getting louder, closer. Angry voices. Crying and screaming. A man was standing in front of him. An angry man he didn’t recognise. He had an envelope in his hand. It was ripped, and the man was holding up two halves of a twenty-dollar bill.
    ‘What the fuck?’
    The angry man was on the porch blocking any escape. Snarling. Wide-eyed righteous anger.
Jo moved backwards and felt the porch chair at the back of his knees. As he sat, the porch chair creaked with his weight and then broke depositing him onto flaking floor timbers. The man stood over him, and Jo raised an arm across his face and moving his other arm across his body, bracing himself for kicks from the size ten boots in sharp focus ahead of him.
‘Please, I can’t remember your name, but please…’
    ‘My name? We’ve never met.’ There was a softness to the words that allowed Jo to uncurl a little and look up.
    ‘You’re Mary-Lou’s man? We met once in Boise, Idaho? She’d gone to meet you. I brought her back on the Greyhound.’
    ‘I ain’t never been to Idaho.’
    The boots receded; the man was now off the porch and hugging a woman and the small girl. He tried to focus on the woman. His mouth felt dry, and his voice weak and cracking, as he tried to shout her name.
    ‘Mary-Lou, please… Mary-Lou, I’m sorry… please read my letter, I never meant no …’
The dry Arizona wind took the last of his words and blew them away towards the setting sun. Jo crawled back inside and collapsed onto the sofa. He could see his reflection in the blackness of the dead television screen. He reached for the whiskey bottle and drank to switch it off. 
***
There was no way of telling what day it was. The grey hues of dusk and dawn were clues enough to determine the time to eat. Seasons announced themselves in obvious ways, and that was enough for Jo. So, when the angry man appeared again, Jo wasn’t sure how much time had lapsed. The house felt cold though, and the picture of Mary-Lou was no longer on the wall but lay smashed on the floor. Had he done this? Perhaps the angry man? He felt a hand on his shoulder shaking him, a cautious, gentle shake. A caring touch. Jo had shaken the delivery boy’s hand once but struggled to remember a connection like this. More hands and arms folded around his shoulders as he was lifted to an upright position; his back responded with a searing bolt of pain. He heard the sounds of glass being swept, and a smell of coffee, dark with chocolate notes, waft across his face. A warm fleece, velveteen smooth, wrapped him and covered his nakedness.
 ‘Mr Pauli? Please put these on.’
 Jo felt the coolness of the metal frames of his glasses. Faces he didn’t recognise were busying themselves in his house. He should be angry, he should get up and demand an explanation. He felt a vibration on the sofa. Someone was sitting next to him, on the side his wife used to sit. He pressed his glasses against the bridge of his nose to guarantee he would not be confused by a blurred image of the past. A woman, with a young girl sitting on her lap, looked at him. Smiling, the young girl spoke first.
 ‘Mr Pauli, I’m sorry.’
 Rising from a wooden tray placed across his lap, steam from a chicken broth fogged his glasses.
 ‘Mr Pauli, I’ve made some of my chicken soup. It’s awful healing. I do so hope you like it,’ said the woman.
 Jo lifted a spoon of broth to his lips and took in the subtleties of its aroma. Cumin, coriander and lemongrass. A glass of iced lemonade tasted sharp and fresh. His tongue searched for an alcohol rush but found only the coolness of the ice. 
 ‘Thank you, it’s delicious. I can’t remember when I last ate something as good as this.’
The man, woman and little girl came into a sharper focus for Jo. It wasn’t Mary-Lou, he was sure of that now at least, which meant it couldn’t be Sophie either. The house was tidy, the floor clear of debris and the furniture replaced right ways up.
‘I’ve fixed some of the lamps,’ said the angry man, except he wasn’t angry any more. His voice was deep and gentle. It matched and mirrored the woman’s voice.
Jo was warm, well fed, and kind voices, gentle whispers, floated on the air around him. He stroked the fleece covering his lap.
‘Am I dead? I ain’t never felt a cloth like that on earth, and that’s for sure.’
 ‘Why, Mr Pauli, that’s just plain old velveteen. I appreciate that you like it though. I have one myself for winter’s evenings,’ said the woman. 
As the tray was lifted from his lap, he could sense the woman shifting closer.
‘We are your new neighbours, although goodness knows we ain’t been as neighbourly as we oughta.’
Jo felt a hand enclose his. A soft stroke of fingers on the back of his hand.
‘This is Milly. My daughter. I’m guessing that you have a granddaughter, about the same age? Sophie?’
‘Yes, I do. They, Sophie and Mary-Lou, were here a little while back… but… well… it all went wrong. Did you meet them?’
‘No, Mr Pauli, that was us. Milly kicked her ball over into your garden and came to ask for it back.’
‘I see.’
‘There was an envelope you gave to Milly, and we kinda figured the story out...’
The little girl sprang off her mother’s lap and stood in front of Jo.
‘I am sorry I made you unhappy. I read your letter, and you write pretty, and I liked the story and hope you see Sophie one day.’
Delivered in the manner of well-rehearsed lines from a school play, the little girl finished with a curtsy and leaned forward to give Jo a small peck on the cheek. She dropped the sellotaped halves of a twenty-dollar bill, into his lap.
‘It’s a beautiful letter, Mr Pauli,’ said the woman, snuggling her daughter back into her lap, ‘I do so hope you will write it out again and post it.
‘So, you read it then?’
‘Yes, I do hope you take no offence. It has quite captivated Milly. She has difficulty with her reading, but your letter… well, it was different, ignited something in her. She’s reading and writing more than ever now and trying to figure out who the characters are and how…  it might end.’
‘It’s not a story, this is my life, you all know that, right?’
‘I know, Mr Pauli. I’m sorry we have taken a lot of your time but when we saw you like… well, you know… we felt we needed to … wanted to help.’
Jo’s head felt clear for the first time in a long while and his vision was sharp. He removed the velveteen blanket and stood up.
‘Where is your husband?’
‘Gary, his name is Gary, and I’m Karen by the way. We are the Oldfields. Gary manages the Wandle Mill restaurant and hotel on Park Hill. We moved from Maine. We love the area. I’m sorry we haven’t been around to check… to say hello to you before now.’
Gary now stood next to his wife and encouraged them towards the door.
‘I’ve taken the liberty to change a few bulbs for you, Mr Pauli,’ said Gary shaking Jo’s hand. ‘Winter’s here, and it gets dark so early now. I get a lorry load of bulbs from the hotel, so it’s no bother.’
‘Thank you. Please call me Jo.’
‘Ok, Jo. I’ve put some bread and milk in the fridge out back there. Is there anything else we can do for you now?’
‘Park Hill did you say?’
‘Yes, just completed a new conversion and opened last month. I’m hiring and getting the place ready for the first guests.’
‘Conversion? I guess that would be the old school then.’
‘That’s right, it was a school many years ago. Did you know it back then?’
‘I taught English for thirty years.’ Jo Pauli stopped talking and stared into the middle distance. All those classes of eager-eyed children, anxious parents, Shakespeare, Steinbeck and Hemingway. Here he was now, madder than Lear, a mouse amongst men, an old man gone to sea but catching nothing, empty. Nothing.
‘Oh my,’ said Karen, giving Milly’s shoulders a small squeeze, ‘you see, Milly, that’s why his letter is so beautifully written.’ She turned toward Jo, ‘I do hope you will write the letter out again, Jo. It got ruined, but it is so beautiful, I feel sure your daughter would love to receive it.’
Milly ran forward and gave Jo a tight hug. ‘Please Mr Pauli, I want to know how it ends.’
‘That’s enough now, Milly,’ said Gary as he opened the door. ‘Karen, Milly come on now we must let Jo get some rest.’ 
 ‘I’ll come by for the dishes another time, Jo. I do hope we can be good neighbours.’
 ‘That best portion of a good man’s life, his little, nameless, unremembered acts, of kindness and of love. Tell me who said that, Milly, and you can visit again.’
Milly giggled and waved goodbye and left with her mother back to the house next door.
 Gary hesitated on the steps and then returned to Jo standing on the doorway.
‘Very poetic, Jo.’
‘It’s Wordsworth, in case she can’t find out.’
‘Look, we’re creating a brochure for the hotel telling the story of the area and the old school. Marketing guys say the guests like that kind of stuff. Would you be interested in some work? It doesn’t pay a lot, but I’d love you to get the gig, if that suited you.’
‘I’ll think about it. Not sure I want to trawl through all those memories. Let me think about it.’
‘Sure thing, Jo. You have a good night.’
‘Hey Gary, I appreciate what you’re trying to do. She’s a beautiful little girl. You should be very proud.’
Jo closed and bolted the door after Gary left. He sat back on the sofa and stared at the television. Writing again? About the school? Barbed memories to prick and irritate the present. He sat on the sofa and wiped a hunk of fresh bread around the rim of the soup bowl. There was love. He was sure of that once. Love, then something bad, and then loss. Could he write again? Could he create stories? Preserve in ink, as black as once were the photographs of his past, the life of the school, his wife, Mary-Lou and Sophie? Where love and memory mingle, nothing is ever truly lost. He stared into the matte black of the television screen and searched for a glimpse of courage on the blurred image of his face..
‘If you are to die alone, Jo Pauli, what better way than in facing fearful odds, for the memory of your family, and the temples of your gods.’  
***
And so it was that Jo, over the following months, would write stories about the old school, the church and the post office, now an Internet cafe. He would fashion from sepia glimpses fierce headmasters, unruly children and unlikely alumni. The copy editors loved it, and the Hotel flourished. Jo introduced stories of benign ghosts and soon coach loads of ghoul loving enthusiasts were booking rooms. Karen, Milly and Gary would visit at the weekends and Milly would stay behind and beg Jo to read her his latest story.
 ‘She so loves your stories, Jo,’ said Karen, tousling Milly’s hair. ‘Her grades have improved, and she doesn’t shy away from some of the more difficult books. We are so grateful for your lessons. I do hope she ain’t no bother to you.’
‘Come here, Milly.’ Jo tapped the sofa seat next to him and placed his whiskey onto the side table.
When Milly sat, he stood and gestured for Karen to take his seat.
‘I’ve got a surprise for you both.’
Jo disappeared into the kitchen and returned a short while later bearing two boxes, secured by two pink ribbons.
‘Why, Mr Jo, you should not be spending your money on presents,’ said Karen, as she tugged at the bow.
Milly was ahead of her and had removed the box lid and pulled out two pens and a leather covered notebook.
‘Mummy, look we’ve got pens and paper.’
‘Well, I have some beautiful chocolates, Milly.’
Karen leant over and kissed Milly on the forehead, and then stood to do the same to Jo.
‘My, that is so thoughtful of you, Jo. Thank you.’
‘It’s a small thing really. I have some money in my pocket and not a little self-respect here too. Jo tapped his chest. ‘All thanks to your Gary and your good selves too. He picked up his whiskey and raised it in a gentle toast towards Karen and Milly.
‘Why I can even afford full price whiskey now.’ He drained the glass, placing it next to the nearly empty bottle of Jack Daniels on the mantlepiece, and then moved towards Milly.
‘Milly, you can help me write some stories for your Daddy’s hotel. Would you like that?’
‘I think we know the answer to that, Jo’, said Karen, trying to pull Milly off Jo, who had flung herself towards him as he advanced, wrapping her arms tightly around him.
‘I’m going to write to Sophie, and Mary-Lou too, and I want to help you write another letter to them, and I think when they know I’m here they’ll want …’
‘You want to interfere, to get nosey about my business, you’ve no right to.’
Jo reached for the whiskey bottle and poured the last of it into his glass, The awkwardness of Milly, who still had one arm clinging round his waist, created a spasm of muscle cramp in his back.
‘Fuck, its empty.’ Jo stumbled back towards the television rubbing his neck. He downed the last slug of Jack Daniels and in the process pushed down on Milly’s head to free himself of her embrace.
Milly fell backwards, hitting her head on the chair’s arm post. A small egg-sized lump appeared on her head with alarming speed.
‘Milly, come here my darling, now,’ said Karen, ‘we need to leave.’ 
Jo, still rubbing his neck, ignored her question.
‘All I know is my business is my business.’
‘I just wanted to help you write your story. You’re a horrid man, I hate you, I hate you. I bet Sophie hates you too, that’s why you’re alone, and Mary-Lou hates…’
Jo turned threw his glass at them. ‘Enough! Get out.’
No more words were exchanged. Into the silence that followed the smashed glass, poured regrets and shame that weighed so heavily on Jo, he collected another whiskey bottle from the kitchen to lighten them. He took a milk chocolate praline and crunched it loudly. He cleared his mouth of its debris with several slugs and then fell into a deep sleep.
***
A titmouse settled itself on a spindle of splintered wood jutting out from the eave of Jo’s bedroom and joined in the dawn’s chorus. Jo threw his shoe at it and the bird flew off immediately. 
He reached up for the top of the bedstead and pulled himself to a sitting position, swung his legs over the side of the bed and fell to the floor. He crawled to a small writing table on the other side of the room and drank the remains of a small water bottle there. 

My dearest Milly,
‘The fool doth think he is wise, but the wise man knows himself to be a fool.’
I did a bad thing. I’m sorry. You don’t hurt people you love. I’m sorry.
Shortly after my wife died, my daughter got pregnant from a man that hit her and then left her. I punched him, and her too, for different reasons. That’s my secret, Milly and now you know. Now it’s our secret.
Meeting you should have been a lifeline for me, a rope from which I could pull myself to shore and secure a future. Instead, it is a rope which I have let slip through my desperate grasp. I remain drifting, clinging to empty whiskey bottles to stay afloat. Maybe one day my Sophie will understand me like I hope you do. Maybe one day, perhaps Christmas Day, oh how I wish it would be Christmas Day, Sophie will bring me a lovely present. Perhaps, one day. Remember Milly, ‘It is not in the stars to hold our destiny but in ourselves.’
So, here’s to secrets and sharing! Be bold, be yourself, and work hard at school, Milly,
Love ‘Grandpa’ Jo.
PS I hope your head is better.

He took a slow stock of his room. A row of books neatly squashed between two horse-shaped bookends, and a small blue sculpt of a whirling dervish, framed each end of the television stand. A candle block of five-wicks burned on the coffee table. The candlelight cast a soft yellow glow that melded with the intense, sad silence of the room. A rocking chair, flower vase, and plumped cushions preserved in the aspic mood of the room. He folded the letter and placed it into an envelope. He sat and, in the silence, could hear the ticking of a silver carriage clock. Its relentless metronome soothed him. He would ask the corner store boy to deliver the letter to Milly tomorrow. That would be that. As he joined the silence of the room once more, Jo counted along with the rhythmic ticking and drank his whiskey until there was nothing left to think about.
***
Christmas was fast approaching judging by the fairy lights appearing on front porches, and the large conifers strapped to roof racks of passing traffic. Jo had missed a few deadlines for the hotel magazine, which meant a return to the discounted whiskey. Since the incident, there had been no contact with any of the Oldfields. So, when he saw Karen approaching the porch-way from the upstairs lobby, his mood lifted, and he rushed down the stairwell opening the door in a breathless hurry.
 ‘Karen, it’s so great to see you, I’ve…’
‘Mr Jo Pauli, I have a warrant to search your house and environs. Please step outside.’
A smart looking man brushed passed him, dressed in the black-tie uniform of the Arizona State Police. Another officer held Karen in a tight embrace as if she might fling herself forward at Jo on sight if released. Jo could see Gary below the porch stairs with a torch crouching and sweeping its beam around the base of the house.
‘Karen, what is this? Why are the police searching my house?’
‘Milly is missing. We found her story. How could you? We trusted you. Why didn’t you tell us you were… seeing her?’
‘What? Seeing her? I don’t know anything, we haven’t spoken in a while not since, you know, not since…Milly hurt herself.’
‘You’ve got a record. Abusing your daughter.’
‘Karen, you don’t understand. It’s not like that. I told you, in the letter.’
‘What letter?’
‘I wrote a letter to you. No, wait, I wrote it to Milly. After she hit her head. I asked the corner store boy to deliver it?’
The police officer took out her notebook.
‘You say you have communicated with Milly, Mr Pauli?’
‘No, yes, look this is all wrong. Yes, I wrote a letter, a letter of apology to Milly. I assumed you’ve seen it, Karen. It wasn’t supposed to be a secret.’
‘What was in the letter, Mr Pauli.’
‘Nothing really. It was months ago. I tried to keep it simple for Milly. I said sorry. Said that I’d been upset when my wife died and had … had hit my daughter, hit her when I shouldn’t and that was why I was on my own. I told her to work hard at school. That was all. I swear. I swear it, Karen.’
‘She’s not here,’ said the police officer who had reappeared on the porch and now joined by Gary. ‘We need to ask you some questions down at the station, Mr Pauli.’
‘Please, ask me your questions here. Let’s not waste time, I don’t need a lawyer, I want to help, really I do.’
The female officer nodded at her colleague.
‘Given the circumstances, we agree, but first I must caution you that you have the right to remain silent. Anything you say can and will be used against you in a court of law. You have the right to an attorney. If you cannot afford an attorney, one will be provided for you. Do you understand the rights I have just read to you? With these rights in mind, do you wish to speak to me?’
‘Yes, I understand and yes, I’m happy to speak with you, with all of you. I said so, didn’t I?’
‘When did you last see Milly?’
‘I can’t remember the date, but it was when she hit her head here. Karen was with us.’
‘But you say you have written to her since then?’
‘Yes, the next day, I think. Like I said I got the corner store boy to deliver it.’
‘How many letters have you written? Did Milly write back?’
‘No, I assumed Mum…’ he looked towards Karen who was in a tight embrace with Gary and slowly rocking backwards and forwards on the sofa. ‘I assumed Karen and Gary didn’t approve.’
‘Tell me exactly what was in the letter, Mr Pauli. Did you ask her to do anything for you? Come over, keep a secret, anything like that.’
‘No, of course not. I told you I apologised. She’s a great kid. She wanted to write about my family, my girl, my granddaughter and I got mad. I’d been drinking. Karen, Gary I am so sorry, but I have nothing to do with this.’
Karen released herself from Gary’s embrace and came to sit next to Jo. The female police officer attempted to restrain her.
‘This was her last story, Girls and Boys.’ Karen held out a collection of loose-leafed paper. ‘It’s about girls that run away and an old man that hits them. A man that hits his daughter, who runs away. It’s about you. She must have been frightened. What have you done to our daughter?’
Jo took the loose leafed papers and started to read. A small tear trickled to the corner of his mouth and dropped onto the top of the page. He smudged it over the title area.
‘Girls an’ Boys, a story by Milly Oldfield.’
‘Except, she’s spelt it all wrong as usual,’ said Gary, taking the papers back from Jo and handing them back to the Police officer.
Jo stood and moved to the mantelpiece and took down the picture of Mary-
Lou and handed it to the police officer.
‘This is my daughter. Her address and telephone number are on the back. I expect if you ring it you will find there is another little girl missing tonight too.’
Jo returned to the sofa and smiled at Karen. ‘This is my fault. I do know where she is.’
Karen recoiled at the news and began to wretch. Gary flung himself towards Jo and was restrained by the police officer. His female colleague removed her handcuffs and took Jo’s arm forcefully behind his back.
No, please just read her story. It’s the most beautiful story she’s ever written. She’s not writing to herself, she’s writing to another little girl. She’s telling you that’s where she has gone.’
Gary, breathing hard, relaxed his grip of the police officer.
‘What do you mean?’
‘Gary, Karen, Milly hasn’t spelt anything wrong, you see. The title isn’t Girls an’ Boys, it’s Girlies in Boise.’
It’s a pun, a joke I used to tell her that cheered me up. Boise, Idaho. Where Mary-Lou and Sophie live. 
Jo, released from the officer’s grip, moved next to Karen and beckoned Gary to join him.
She’s coming home, Karen and she’s bringing my granddaughter with her. Gary, she’s bringing me my Christmas present. How far her little candle throws its beams! So shines a good deed in a naughty world.’
***

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">The Innocent Neighbour The sweet converse of an innocent mind - John Keats</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Choice</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The-Choice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Choice" /><published>2021-02-06T18:19:44+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-06T18:19:44+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The-Choice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/06/The-Choice.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;The Choice&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt; “Her lips touched his brain as they touched his lips, as though they were a vehicle of some vague speech and between them he felt an unknown and timid pleasure, darker than the swoon of sin, softer than sound or odor.” 
― James Joyce&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot; &gt;
Billy Sepps had a choice to make. Turn right, to walk past the commuter cafes, would be quicker. Turn left, perhaps the better claim, would take him through an elegant curve of cherry blossom trees. His interview was not until 9:30 a.m, so he had time to decide. He cut left, into Savile Row. He would come to learn later, when he was older, when life had pummelled wisdom deep inside him, when choices begat choices and way lead on to way, that it was the trees that drew him left.
    ‘Too much poetry in your head, Son,’ his father would say.
‘Nonsense,’ his grandfather would retort.
When Dad left, Billy and Grandad filled the void by reading together. They read anything and everything, voraciously. And so it was, Billy Sepps excelled at school and university. And so it was, Billy Sepps landed a prestigious job interview. And so it was, two roads to choose from, Billy Sepps, blue-eyed romantic, decided on the one less travelled by.
It was one of those crisp spring mornings that demanded optimism, even from a Monday. He’d slept on a friend’s sofa to avoid being late and now, with some time at hand, stopped to check his reflection in the large shop window of Bookers, Gentleman Tailors. He passed judgement on both profiles in turn and posed with jacket closed and then opened. He licked his hand and ran it back through his hair to fix an errant mop of blonde fringe. The suit had been his Grandfather’s, a classic blue double-breasted barathea twill, worn partly for luck but mostly as evidence that something of substance from his family, something good, had survived. Old suits have character and like the old men from whom they are borrowed, often crease and behave as they choose. He tried to remember the feel of his Grandfather’s consoling hugs and conjure his whispered advice into vivid reality.
’Take your chances, Son. Suck on life’s marrow, open your heart to people, and tell the truth, boy.’
As he tried to make the suit his own, he noticed his brogues were covered in a fine film of dust. He buffed each shoe in turn against the faded fabric of his trousers. Some of the shoe scuffs were just too old and deep to budge. He brought his face close to the window and began a series of facial exercises to ensure that his dimpled smile would be at its practised best when he checked in at the reception. As he pulled his widest grin, tongue fully extended, he noticed an immaculately dressed elderly man just inside the main door. In a vain attempt to reclaim an air of nonchalance he removed a letter from his jacket pocket in a pretence to check his interview timings. 
A jangle of keys was followed by a low creak from the shop door as it swung open.
‘Are you looking for shoes and a suit, for your interview, young man?’ said the old man, stepping out of the gloomy interior and filling the main door frame.
‘Good morning, Sir,’ said Billy, checking his watch, ‘just making the best of the one I’ve got if I’m honest.’
‘It’s a fine suit.’ The old man stood to the side of the door and extended his arm in a gesture of welcome. ‘Come inside; we have an automated shoe polisher. No charge.’
‘Thank you. I will.’
Billy folded the letter and replaced it into his jacket pocket and followed the old man to the back of the shop. On his way, Billy ran his hands over large rolls of assorted fabrics, packed into cubicles and measuring benches. Two large cutting tables took up the majority of the rear of the shop, pushed up against mahogany walls. Statuesque mannequins, sporting chalked up double-breasted suits of varying pinstripe, formed a guard of honour as Billy ventured into the heart of the store.
‘You’re open early? Are you stocktaking?’ 
‘You’ll find the professional people we serve are awake a lot earlier than this young man. You’ll do well to remember that.’ The old man removed a cloth cover from a large free-standing shoe polisher and pointed to the spot where Billy should place his foot.
Billy felt reproached.
‘Yes, of course, I just meant… how did you know I have an interview by the way?’
‘A guess,’ said the old man as he switched on the polisher. He placed a small blob of black polish onto the end of a long swab-stick and smeared a little onto the toe caps of Billy’s shoes gesturing to Billy to place his foot against the rotating brushes. ‘I recognised the header of the letter you were reading.’
‘I’m impressed,’ said Billy
‘Yes, it’s producing a nice shine.’ The old man smeared a little more polish this time onto the heel area and increased the spin speed of the brushes.
‘No, I meant with your guess.’
‘Oh, well we have all the partners in here for their fittings. They take a particular interest in sartorial elegance. Pluckey men, best-dressed crooks in the business.’ The old man fixed his gaze on Billy, raising an eyebrow that seemed to ask how his little joke had gone down.  
Billy, unresponsive, looked down at his shoes and noticed the large toe scuffs were still evident, although toned down a little. 
‘Pluckeys?’
‘Plume, Tuckey and Sperns. That’s right isn’t it? I saw the P, T and S on the envelope. It's what we call them here.’
‘I see, thank you. If I get a job, I promise I’ll come back and buy a complete outfit from you. You’ve been very kind.’ Billy waited for the polisher to spin down to a quiet crawl and then removed his foot. ‘I’d best be off as I don’t want to be late.’
‘Well, you should let me fit you one now.’
‘That would be great, but I couldn’t’
‘Why not?’
‘Well for a start the chance of a job is slim. It’s a two-day interview, and that’s if you make the first-day cut, and hundreds of candidates for a single job. I don’t have the time for a fitting, and well I don’t have any money for a deposit either.’
Billy thanked the old man once more and moved to the doorway.’
‘Young man, I like to think of myself as someone who knows the measure of a man.’
Billy turned around but couldn’t see the old man. He heard a rustle of fabric behind the first row of mannequins. The old man appeared with an Oxford blue, faint check suit draped over his arm. In his hand, the shiniest black shoes, with thick liquorice leather laces, that Billy had ever seen.
‘Please, try these for size.’
‘I couldn’t, I simply can’t afford it.’
‘Consider it an investment, young man. I have a hunch you’ll come back to Bookers. You can pay for these whenever you can.’
‘I don’t know what to say.’
‘Just your word young man, that is all I require.’
‘Well, yes, of course, that’s easy, you have my word, thank you.’
‘Not so easy in the keeping as in the giving, I’d wager for most.’ He draped the clothes over Billy’s arm, placed the shoes into Billy’s hand and pointed to the changing rooms.
Billy emerged a few minutes later.
‘It’s incredible, a perfect fit.’
‘As I said, I’m a good judge of the measure of a man. I’ll keep your old clothes here.’ He took Billy’s old suit and shoes and hung them carefully onto a nearby rail. ‘Good luck young man, I wish you well.’ He removed the interview envelope from the inside pocket of the old suit jacket and handed it to Billy. ‘Just a word of caution young man,’ he said before releasing the envelope, ‘everyone knows a Bookers’ suit when they see one. Make sure they see the real you underneath.’
Billy checked the letter was still inside the envelope.
‘Thank you, again I don’t know how to …’
But the old man was gone, disappeared between the thick curtain drapes of the changing area and the mountainous rolls of suit fabrics. Billy left the shop, checked his watch, and continued left along the cherry tree lane, to his date with the future. 
***
The offices of Plume, Tuckey and Sperns, occupied all fifteen floors of an impressive Art Deco building on Frith street. Billy thought it looked like a hotel. As he approached, he noticed a dandy looking doorman, in a red frock coat and sable top hat, hailing taxis and opening doors for a procession of smart looking men and women.
‘Good morning Mr …’ Billy squinted against the strong morning sun that was reflecting from, and partially obscuring, the doorman's name badge, ‘… Dennis?’
‘That’s right, Sir. Good morning.’ Dennis replied, ‘Interviews?’
    ‘God, is it that obvious?’
    Dennis laughed, held open the door and stepped inside after Billy. ‘You’re not the first well-dressed youngster here this morning, although I’ve got to say your shoes win the best-polished prize for sure and the suit Sir, well it speaks for itself.’
    ‘That might come in handy today I expect. I’ll give it the tricky questions.’
    ‘Excellent Sir, very droll. It’s straight through the double doors, swing left, and you’ll see they’ve set up a special reception desk. Good luck, Mr… ‘ Dennis pointed at his name badge as if to prompt Billy for his name.
    ‘Oh, yes, Billy, Billy Sepps,’ said Billy extending his hand.
    Dennis raised his hands as he retreated towards the door.
     ‘Need to keep the white gloves clean, Sir. Best of luck to you, and your suit, Mr Sepps.’
    Dennis took a few steps backwards and, with a gentle bow, swivelled on his polished boots and returned outside. 
The door immediately swung open again and silhouetted against the streaming light was the figure of a woman. Billy stood transfixed by the shapes and curves slinking towards him. The greys of the silhouette started to transform into a palette of hues; flesh pink, sap green and the most vivid blue eyes fixing him to the spot. The air, subtly sweetened with delicate notes of elderflower and jasmine, spiralled around Billy in a gentle vortex. Billy felt he was looking at a giant cover picture from Vogue. A perfection of form, proportion and poise and standing directly in front of him.
    ‘Julie Peterson-Harris.’
A hand extended towards Billy and, without knowing quite why, he gently held it between his thumb and index finger and kissed it.
‘You are sweet. The door chappie said you were going to the same place as me.’
‘Dennis.’
‘Very pleased to meet you, Dennis. Are you nervous? I am.’
‘No,…’
‘Amazing, I do so love a confident man. Come on let’s check in.’ Julie Peterson-Harris flicked her finely brushed blonde hair behind her with a casual twitch of her head, hooked her arm into Billy’s and guided him forward. ‘Show the way then. I say, wouldn’t it be amazing if we end up working together here. I do hope so. My Grandfather trained here in the fifties although I don’t expect that will count for much anymore. By the way, your suit is to die for.’
As they approached the chrome veneered reception desk, Julie removed her arm and stepped ahead of Billy. 
‘Julie Peterson-Harris. Training contract interviews.’ She reached inside her Salvatore Ferragamo bag and produced a matching leather portfolio from which she slid out her invitation letter.
‘Thank you, Miss Harris, please take a seat in reception, Zone-B.’
‘That’s Peterson-Harris,’ said Julie as she snatched back her letter. She turned to Billy. ’Bloody reception can’t even get a simple name right. Good luck, Dennis. Probably see you at one of the breaks.’
‘Sure, that would be nice, but…’
    Julie Peterson-Harris was gone, and Billy watched her slink to Zone B, noting the turning heads and stolen looks of those she passed.
‘Mr Dennis? Mr Dennis, have you got your paperwork with you?’
Billy reached into the inside pockets of his new jacket. So many pockets. The fabric still felt unfamiliar to him. 
‘It’s Billy, not Dennis,’ said Billy, offering his crumpled letter to the receptionist.
‘Oh, I thought the young lady said… Never mind.’ She took the letter from Billy and searched the candidate list. ‘Got you, although I’d suggest you address the partners with your correct name, Mr William Sepps.
‘Yes, of course, sorry to have confused.’
‘No problem, Zone-D please.’
    Billy had been immediately disappointed with the direction to go to a different reception zone. Jesus, get a grip of yourself, Billy Sepps. You’ve met her for less than five minutes and she didn’t even get your name right. But deep in the evolutionary pit of his soul, where sober reflection doesn't exist, something had stirred. Billy arrived at Zone-D and poured himself a coffee, even though he had no strict need of one. There was no view of Zone B, and for a while Billy was glad. He sipped his coffee, chatted to a collection of candidates and waited.
***
The room was dark with spot lamps creating cool pools of blue light on the desk ahead of the interviewers. The effect was to create a silhouette effect around them much like an actor might experience an audience. To Billy, they all seemed to have one face, giant and blank as a row of New York cheesecakes.
‘I hope you are well researched, Mr Sepps,’ said the portly man in the middle of the five-man interview panel.
‘Researched? Yes, well, of course. Amongst city firms, Pluckeys offers the chance to work on high-level deals, often with an international component, but with the increased responsibility and involvement that accompanies a smaller intake of trainees. This responsibility fosters a more active and creative role in clients’ transactions, a more personal working environment, and closer client contact, all of which is attractive …’ 
    Billy paused as he noted the Chair of the panel had raised his hand.
The portly man was laughing, and the other cheesecakes seem to be trying hard not to.
‘Have you quite finished, Sir John?
    ‘Sorry, I thought you wanted to know about my research into the firm,’ said Billy scanning the panel for some confirmation of humanity. ‘What do you mean, Sir John?’
    ‘Gielgud. You’ve memorised and delivered your lines well, young man.’
    ‘Sorry, yes, it helps to overcome the nerves, but I did mean it, the bit about taking responsibility as a sole trainee.’
    ‘Did you mean the bit about Pluckeys too?’
    ‘Pluckeys? Oh no, did I say that? Look I’m so sorry, I meant no disrespect. I only learnt the term this morning at Bookers.’
    ‘The tailors?’
    ‘Yes, there was an old man, he polished my shoes… he knew the firm … best dressed ... never mind, look I’m really sorry.’
    ‘It will take more than a Booker’s suit, Mr Sepps, to impress our clients.’
    ‘Of course, I can promise you that I will try to harness and capitalise on…’
    ‘No more clichés please.’
    The panel continued to ask their standard questions and although Billy couldn’t gauge his performance from the vanilla complexions of the committee he felt he had been fluent and comprehensive.
    ‘Where will you be taking the suit to celebrate Mr Sepps if you are successful in your application?’
    ‘Back to the shop to get my old one, it’s on loan.’
    The cheesecakes were laughing again.
    ‘Very droll, Mr Sepps. We’ve never had a trainee in a Booker’s suit before. We are not impressed with tricks, deceptions and twists of the truth. Our clients want content Mr Sepps, content, not a smart shell.’
    ‘Yes, of course, I didn’t mean to suggest…’
    ‘That’s enough Mr Sepps. There is a door behind you. Please use it, order some refreshment and await our response.’
    ‘Thank you,’ Billy stood up and with one hand fastened his top jacket button, ‘about this suit, I am more than just a …’
    ‘Enough now, Mr Sepps. The far door, please.’
***
‘Dennis, Dennis… over here.’
    Billy was being hailed across the room by Julie Peterson-Harris. Billy noticed an odd sense of pride in being the focus of attention from such a beautiful woman. 
    ‘Julie, hi, how did it go?’
    ‘Great, except I can’t remember all the embellishments I put on my CV and I’ve winged so many questions that I’m bound to be tripped up tomorrow. Lying is hard work isn’t it?’
    ‘Tomorrow? So you’ve got through to tomorrow then?’
    ‘Yes, of course, silly.’
    ‘Why of course?’
    ‘Where are we, Mr Dennis?’
    ‘Look about that. My name is Billy, not Dennis’
    ‘Why did you tell me it was Dennis? You can’t lie about that; they’d spot that before you sat down.’
‘What? No, I’m not lying to anyone about anything. Look, it’s the doorman’s name, you just got confused when…’
    They were interrupted by a waitress in a cream pressed pinafore bearing the Pluckey’s motto, ‘semper innocentes’ in an ornate calligraphic style.
‘Can a take your order Sir, Madam.’
    The waitress pointed to the menu cards on the table, propped up against a small vase that contained a single white orchid.
‘I’ll take a flat white, and the selection of finger sandwiches a la jour,’ said Julie without referencing the card. 
Billy picked up the card and sensed there wasn’t time to interpret the French descriptions. ‘ I’ll have the same. Thank you.’ Billy held out the small menu card.
    The waitress smiled at Billy, took the card and propped it back up against the vase.
    ‘That will be all,’ said Julie, successfully removing the waitress’ smile.
    ‘You see now, Dennis?’
    ‘Billy.’
    ‘Yes, Silly Billy is much better.’
    Julie Peterson-Harris leaned forward and without taking her eyes off Billy’s delivered a coquettish flutter of her eyelids, while handing him the recently replaced menu card. ‘Read the top line. Where are we?’
Billy didn’t want to look anywhere else but into her eyes, however, he knew he could not resist a direct instruction from her. Julie moved across onto the banquette, closer to Billy, and removed the flap of his jacket pocket that had turned inside itself.
‘That’s better. Wow, this is a Booker’s suit. I’m impressed.’
Billy read out the top line of the menu card, ‘Café d'affaires des Partenaires.’
‘This must have cost a small fortune. Ten, fifteen thousand pounds?’
‘I hope not; it’s on loan. If I get the job, I’ve promised to go back and pay for it.’
Julie appeared to take the conversation about the suit as implicit permission to touch it. She stroked the cool fabric of Billy’s arm, gently squeezing his bicep in the process.
    ‘Boy, you must be some negotiator, Silly Billy.’
    ‘Not really, I think the old man took pity on me, to be honest. He didn’t even ask my name now I come to think about it.’
    ‘What? So if you don’t get the job you’ve bagged a 15k-suit. Clever.’
    ‘Well…’ Billy was interrupted by the return of the waitress who placed down a rosette of fine cut finger sandwiches and two coffees each bearing a fleur-de-lys stencilled cream topping. The central petals of Julie’s stencil had bent slightly making it look more like a trident. The plates bore the company’s motto in a translucent calligraphic glaze around their edge. Always innocent.
    ‘Look my French isn’t great but doesn’t this just say the Business cafe?’
    ‘Yes, said Julie, picking up a small oblong egg and watercress sandwich, ‘but it’s the Partner’s cafe.’ A small petal of watercress fell onto Julie’s knee. Billy reached across to pick it up, taking several clumsy attempts at it.
    ‘Sorry, I didn’t mean to … there was a piece of …’
    ‘It’s fine’ said Julie who had placed her hand over his, securing it in place over her knee. ‘Why don't you try some?’
    ‘Yes, yes I will.’ Billy, with his free hand, picked a sandwich and put it under his nose to detect the filling.
    ‘It’s not a cigar, Silly Billy.’
    Julie leaned her head closer to Billy’s and whispered into his ear. ‘The partner’s cafe is where you get sent to if you pass the first day. The others get sent back to the zones to hear the bad news. One of the flunkies will be giving you a letter like mine any minute now. Julie waved an envelope, heavily embossed with large golden lettering, P, T and an S. Look around you how many candidates do you see?’
Billy swept his gaze around the room as he stuffed a sandwich into his mouth. An unpleasant anchovy, caper and olive tamponade insulted his taste buds. He swallowed quickly, managing to splutter a little out onto his chin in the process. Julie stood, tossed him a serviette and moved to the window area. Billy saw that most tables were filled with well-dressed men and women, most alone, some in pairs, and one larger grouping. Most were well into their thirties and several clusters clearly middle-aged. Most were speaking quietly, earphones blue toothed to mobiles, mumbling to themselves, the best dressed psychiatric ward in London. One man with a worn grey complexion was shuffling papers into and out of a weathered Pluckey’s briefcase. He caught Billy’s stare but then shifted his gaze to take in Julie, who was reapplying a crimson lipstick via her compact mirror.
‘I don’t see any of the candidates from my zone, do you, Julie?’ Billy said as he wiped his chin.
‘Exactly. We were shown the door. The door. The one all partners go through. The lucky ones, Silly Billy, Dennis.’
    Julie clicked shut her compact as if it were a clapperboard indicating the end of a scene. ‘Do you want to celebrate, tonight?’
‘What, just us?’
    ‘No, I thought our families could get together and meet. I’m sure you’ve brought loads with you to celebrate.’
    ‘It’s just me. There isn’t anyone.’
    ‘Silly Billy, I know. Of course, I meant just you and little ol’ me.’
    Julie moved over to Billy and pressed a small piece of note paper into his hand as she placed a gentle kiss onto his cheek.
    ‘Who brings relatives anyway? Tomorrow night will be different though if one of us makes it.’
    ‘Why?’ Billy unfolded the note which contained a mobile number and the words ‘Call me.’
    ‘Let me see. You land the biggest job of your life, in the most famous capital on earth, that pays a six-figure sum to its trainees. I expect even old curmudgeonly Silly Billy Dennis would let his guard down and celebrate with Mum and Dad.’
    ‘Of course, yeah, I see.’ Billy rubbed his finger lightly over the note and gestured to Julie to join him back on the banquette. ‘The truth is, Miss Julie Peterson-Harris, that I don’t have any family. No one.’
    ‘What? You’re an orphan?’
    ‘I guess. My mum is dead, and my dad is inside.’
    ‘Inside what?’
    ‘Call yourself a lawyer? Inside.’
    ‘Oh. Then we should celebrate tonight. I’ll be Mum, Dad, Sis and,’ Julie leaned forward to whisper in Billy’s ear, ‘anyone you want me to be. Call me.’
Billy watched Julie slink over to the lifts and momentarily quieten the conversations of those she passed. The waitress returned and handed Billy an envelope.
‘Hello, Sir, I was asked to give you this, Sir.’
Billy took the envelope and watched Julie disappear into the lift. He moved quickly to follow her, placing the note with Julie’s mobile number inside the envelope. As he reached the lift he remembered he hadn’t thanked the waitress. But she was gone, it was too late. In the silvered door of the lift he saw a reflection of a man with a crimson lip impression on his left cheek. The lift doors opened, and both Billy and his reflection disappeared inside. He read his letter twice more in the lift and several times again in the lobby, apologising to people who had failed to avoid his meandering walk to the lobby door. 

Dear Mr William Sepps,

It is with the greatest pleasure that the partners of Plume, Tuckey and Sperns invite you to spend the second day of your contract interview with us in the Connaught Rooms. A working breakfast will be available from 7 a.m. and interviews will commence at 7:30 a.m. promptly. No special preparation is required, although you are to attend in formal business attire.

    So, it wasn’t only Julie that had been accepting about his family. The cheesecakes had a heart. A convict father and roots, like old wisteria, knurled and hooked into the basest elements of working-class life. In this moment of triumph, he felt a weight of sorrow. There was no one with whom Billy could share his good news. The lobby door opened, and Dennis stood to one side and, with a flourish of his arm, welcomed Billy onto the red carpet.
‘I hope it is good news, Mr Sepps?’
‘Dennis, hello, yes, I’ve been invited back. Look.’ Billy waved the envelope in the air.
‘Well, it’s a toss of the coin now, so you make sure you get plenty of rest and well done again, Mr Sepps.’ Dennis hailed a cab which pulled up promptly at the red carpet’s curb.
‘Fifty-fifty? I wish the odds were that good, and please call me Billy.’
‘Oh yes, Mr Sepps, there’s only ever two what is brought back. So, fifty-fifty is the bookies’ odds of you joining the family here, Sir. That’s how we like to think of ourselves, Sir. If it’s all the same to you Mr Sepps you might be starting here tomorrow, proper like. So I’ll keep it formal for now if you understand my reasoning.’
‘Well I …’ But there was no time for further discussion. Dennis shut the door of the taxi and banged on the roof lightly, and the cab pulled away into the London slipstream.
***
Billy hung his Booker’s suit into the small closet of his boutique hotel taking care to avoid butting up to the damp stain on the inside wall. The double bed was hard, and Billy decided not to check the rest of the room too carefully in case it put him off his sleep later. He had called Julie and arranged to meet in a bar nearby. He showered and changed into jeans and white tee-shirt wishing now he had packed for the possibility of a date with the most attractive woman he’d ever met. But this was a day for honesty thought Billy. For me. For who I am. Billy worked some hair gel into his fringe and after several further checks in the hallway mirror and a sniff of both armpits set out to meet Julie.
‘You look nice,’ said Julie, snuggling closer than she strictly needed to on a small chesterfield sofa at the back of the pub. ‘Have you done something with your hair?’
‘No.’ Billy tried to casually comb his hand back through his hair and got stuck in the gel halfway through. He tousled his hair nonchalantly and wiped his hand on the back of his neck. The effect was to produce a tower of hair leaning forward like a unicorn horn. Julie laughed and with a small brush from her bag set about smoothing Billy’s hair into place.
‘There, that’s better, but you’ll have to wash it I think before tomorrow.’ She placed both hands onto the side of his face and leaned in to kiss his forehead. Billy’s view was a blur of soft pastel pink, with impasto crimson and bathed in delicate scents of intoxicating perfume; lime, jasmine, and musk base notes that lingered, transfixing Billy to the spot. The back room was quiet and shielded from view by a large pillar between it and the bar. Lights dimmed, an ochre yellow reflected from oak panelled walls. Irresistible. Billy raised his head a little as Julie aimed her kiss which allowed her to find his lips. A small expiration of breath was the only sign that Julie had been caught by surprise. Julie’s arms fell onto and around Billy’s shoulders pressing him deeper into her body. Soft short caresses of flesh synchronised unrehearsed with tongues as Billy and Julie folded around one another. Irresistible. While deep in their evolutionary spiral Billy became aware of glasses chinking and footsteps entering the snug and leaving promptly. They unfolded a little, allowing Julie to wipe a crimson smear from Billy’s mouth and Billy to straighten Julie’s collar. 
    ‘I’m sorry,’ said Billy, not quite knowing what to do or say next, ‘that was …’
    ‘Nice.’ Julie sat a little straighter and created a small distance between them as a red-faced waiter approached and then disappeared through the swing kitchen doors at the back of the pub. ‘I’d better get some drinks before they throw us out.’
    ‘Let me get them.’ Billy attempted to squeeze out from between the table and sofa.’
Julie giggled. ‘You get the next round when … things have settled a little.’
Billy slid back along the sofa and pretended to tuck his tee shirt into his jeans. After several rounds of drinks and gentle exploration Billy had such a complete sense of satisfaction that he imagined himself cocooned, wrapped in the warm silk of a spiders web, protected, safe. Irresistible. Loved. Julie now knew all about his dad in prison, his humble working-class roots, his mother’s death at her hand. His Grandfather, beloved Grandfather, now ensconced in a home for the demented. She listened, laughed and cried at all the right bits as Billy Sepp’s life gushed before her. Billy tried to remember what he had learned about Julie, but the beer was too strong. Irresistible. Secrets shared. Loved. Innocent, always innocent.
‘You know it’s jush… ‘ Billy laughed, ‘I mean, just us two?’
‘It’s a bit premature for exclusivity, Silly Billy.’ Julie’s wit was as sharp as her diction.
‘No, I mean it’s just us two left in the interviews. One of us is going to get the job.’
‘How do you know that?’
‘Dennis, my good friend, Dennis the menace.’ Billy fell into a fit of giggles. 
‘Then you should have it,’ said Julie, who left the sofa and headed to the bar.
Billy tried to follow her but had difficulty standing. He stood and toppled against the pillar. He watched Julie weave skilfully between tables and customers waiting at the bar. She returned with a bottle of Mumm champagne and two frosted glasses. 
‘Here's to Mr William Sepps, the new Pluckey’s partner.’ Julie helped Billy back to the seat and took a small sip of champagne as she refilled Billy’s glass.
‘Julie, don’t be silly you’ve worked hard too. Whichever of us gets it, we can still see each other?’ Billy tried to read Julie’s face but struggled to focus. ‘Julie?’
Julie clinked her glass against Billy’s and raised another toast. She folded herself around him, just like at their first kiss and stroked his cheek. 
‘Listen to me Silly Billy, I love you.’
‘What?’
‘I think I loved you from the first time I saw you.’
‘I think I … I mean … you smell so nice …’ Billy’s head flopped onto Julie’s shoulder. Irresistible. To be loved. Innocent.
‘You have no family, Billy. This is the start you deserve and … well maybe, I can be part of your life anyway as… Oh, I’m silly.’
‘Family?’ Billy closed his eyes and burrowed his head into the crook of Julie’s neck. Feminine curves remembered. Irresistible. 
‘Yeah, family,’ whispered Julie. ‘You were so handsome, Silly Billy in that suit. Your lucky suit. Irresistible.’ Julie’s words, soft, warm, wormed their way into the fug of Billy’s brain. ‘We’re going home now Billy. We’re going to make love, and we’re going to be together. A family. Forever.’ Julie delivered these final words as a lilting lullaby into Billy’s ear, a siren call, then guided him from the pub back to his hotel room.
Clothes shed, flesh wrapped and folded. More champagne. A toast to family. One. Irresistible. Innocent. Family. To be loved. Billy Sepps fell into Julie’s naked arms, into love, and into a deep, deep sleep of the innocent. Always innocent. The intense notes of sweat and the musk of raw flesh faded, as the cool, sober air of dawn slowly seeped in.
***
Billy woke to the sound of screeching brakes outside his window. He waited for glass and metal sounds that must inevitably follow. Silence. Crisis averted. His head pounded with its lone drummer boy keeping a syncopated rhythm with his pulse rate. His tongue stuck to the roof of his mouth with a thick spittle gel, which tasted two weeks past its sell-by date. Naked and cold, he saw in the detritus of the room scattered clothing. A tee-shirt crumpled by the front door, denim jeans, with one leg turned inside out, on the chair back, socks on the window ledge, pants forlorn at the side of the bed. He wrapped the duvet tightly around him as he attempted to walk to the bathroom. He passed the wardrobe and saw a refined suit hanging with military bearing above a pair of mahogany black shoes. It is then he realised. His clothes were alone.
***
‘Hello, Billy,‘ said Dennis, standing in front of the red carpet door. ‘You OK? It looks like you’ve nicked yourself shaving just there’. Dennis pointed to his own chin, and Billy felt a corresponding sting.
‘Dennis, hello. Look, I’ve overslept, and I need to … you called me, Billy?’
‘That’s right, son and I’m now calling you a taxi.’ Dennis raised his hand and gave a two-fingered whistle to the taxi rank opposite.
‘I need to see Julie. My interview. Julie is …’ Billy felt Dennis’ hand in his low back guiding him away from the door and towards the black cab that had just pulled up.
‘Miss Peterson-Harris won’t be seeing anyone today, tomorrow or for a while. Busy times for her now, Billy, since she joined the family.’
Billy Sepps slumped into the back of the black cab and held his head in both hands as the Frith Building receded into his distant past.
‘Where to, mate?’
Billy had nowhere to go. No one to see. Memories of the night before were hazy. Nothing. He looked through his hands and saw a line of Cherry trees in full bloom.
‘Head towards those trees.’
‘Chartres lane, OK, will do. Where are you going?’
‘I’m not sure, just follow the trees for now.’
‘Somewhere smart I reckon.’
‘Why?’
‘I do a regular pick up at Pluckeys, and I know a Booker’s suit when I see one. Clothes maketh the man, eh?’
Billy looked down at the pressed single trouser pleat, as sharp as the previous morning, the neat hand stitching on the lapel buttonhole, the varnished wood buttons of the jacket and the matt sheen of the dark blue cotton fabric. He began to mumble to himself as he watched the cherry trees fly by the window.
    ‘I shall be telling this with a sigh, somewhere ages and ages hence, two roads diverged in a wood, and I, I took the one less travelled by, and that has made all the difference.’
    ‘I didn’t quite get that, mate.’
    ’Bookers tailors, Savile Row, just take me there,’ said Billy.
    ‘Of course, mate. It’s not the route I’d have chosen, but it’s your choice and we’ll get there, eventually.’
* * *


&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">The Choice “Her lips touched his brain as they touched his lips, as though they were a vehicle of some vague speech and between them he felt an unknown and timid pleasure, darker than the swoon of sin, softer than sound or odor.” ― James Joyce</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bulldog Clip</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/03/Bulldog-Clip.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bulldog Clip" /><published>2021-02-03T23:44:53+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-03T23:44:53+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/03/Bulldog-Clip</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/03/Bulldog-Clip.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Bulldog Clip&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt; “They never fail who die in a great cause.” 
― George Gordon Byron&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;

In a corner of a far flung attic,
disguised by decades’ of dust,
you doggedly grip papers
together, tethered, trapped,
his last Will, a testament
to those he fought with.
&lt;br&gt;
My fingers, three generations on,
squeeze your sides.
Like Arthurian stone,
you release your sword
to one you recognise as your own.
Duty done, you snap back smartly,
Like a square bashed soldier, renewed for action.
&lt;br&gt;
You were the last thing he touched,
in the ditches of France,
entrusted with dark memories
of our freedom’s birth.
I see his fingerprints in the dust,
and place my fingers there,
two sides of the same sheaf.
I place you with his medals.
Its where he would want you
British Bulldog, rest in peace
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="poetry" /><category term="poem" /><summary type="html">Bulldog Clip “They never fail who die in a great cause.” ― George Gordon Byron</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Stroke of Blood</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/01/stroke-ofBlood.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Stroke of Blood" /><published>2021-02-01T19:32:44+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-01T19:32:44+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/01/stroke-ofBlood</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/01/stroke-ofBlood.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;A Stroke of Blood&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt; The tree of liberty must be refreshed from time to time with the blood of tyrants - Thomas Jefferson&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;

Blood. I knew the perfect combination of colours to paint realistic blood. It was a strange thought to have but, like most thoughts, it arose without invitation. Vermillion, an obvious base, but it is the spicule of ultramarine blue and the dab of burnt umber that holds the key. I was improving. Ismael agreed. One day I would paint a masterpiece, sign it, and it would hang in a great Mathaf or a Grand Mosque. People would look at it and discuss me, Amal Haddad, the great painter. I know it is wrong to think like this, but I am becoming good, the best in my class. Ismael I feel has sensed it. I imagine Ismael, working on his canvas. It is an image that keeps coming to me. Uninvited. I can’t resist it. I think these days in colours, in brush strokes, in subtleties of shading and tone. I calculate proportion and form of the objects around me, their pastel hues and outlines. It calms me. My husband, Feras, I think is happier, although no children have come. I tell him to be patient, I have seen them, and Allah will bring me the clay and colours to shape them. Under my abaya, the purple blotches fade unseen. I can paint blood. Real blood. Uninvited.

Judging by the excessive sway of her hips, and the casualness of her amble, Souad had noticed one of the male students, Khalid, setting up an easel near mine.
    ‘You know you have paint over the hem of your abaya, Souad?’
    ‘Oh, really?’ She picked up a brush from my easel and scooping up a blob of burnt sienna from the palette, flicked it at me, ‘And now so do you.’
    She bent down and smeared the freshly landed paint over the lower hem of my abaya. 
    ‘There, that could be Dolce and Gabbana now,’ she said, daubing a couple of spots on my left thigh as she grabbed my leg for support to stand up.
    ‘Careful, Souad, I have a bruise there.’
    ‘Another one? I would kill Nabeel if he did that to me.’ She gave my thigh a small rub and held my gaze for a little longer than was necessary. ‘Anyway, the paint proves we were here.’
    ‘You’ve ruined it. Feras will be furious.’
    ‘You worry too much about my brother, Amal.’
    The art course had been Souad’s idea. It had been a good one too. 
    ‘Come on let’s go,’ she had said when she saw the flyer on my fridge. I’m not sure why I left it there. I just liked the idea of it. I wanted Feras to see it and suggest I go. Maybe.
    ‘Painting? Great, you might like it. Get you out of the house and away from my idiot brother.’
    I did not respond to the insult, which I think gave Souad confidence to push the point. I imagined my future idiot children. When I was a great artist, I would paint their portraits but not with Feras’ fleshy ears or thin lips. One day I would paint Feras how I would like him to be. How I would have chosen if the choice was mine. My daughters will not marry at fourteen. Thick, crimson impasto lips, confident swipes of raw umber hair, titanium-white teeth. Sinews of yellow ochre stretching from burnt sienna muscles, naked, glistening, smeared with acrylic gloss with just enough cadmium red to create soft folds of flesh. I would perfect his form. Uninvited. Such thoughts. Unbidden. My children will not have bruises under their abayas. 
    Nabeel, Souad’s husband, and Feras agreed we could attend the art class on the basis we always went together. Our most modest Hijab garments were to be worn, and an agreement we would never speak with any Kafirs. For the first few weeks, Nabeel drove us and picked us up. The time passed quickly. I was lost in the new processes I was learning. At once both absorbed in the detail of the pure still life, and also elevated, floating outside of my troubles. I loved it.
    The class, held at the Mathaf Museum of Modern art, attracted a mixture of Muslim and western women. That’s what Souad said we should report back anyway.
    ‘We will ignore the men, so why mention them to our husbands?’
    A complication avoided. I preferred to draw. Time at the Mathaf is precious, and I grew bored of these women looking at my eyes within the niqab, asking only about my makeup. Souad was different. Confident. She could mix, display some new jewellery or shoes. This week, a bejewelled iPhone generated animated conversation amongst the women. Jealous. She would often lift her veil too if no men were present. One week she left the scarf off entirely as Ismael came into the room. Souad looked at me, placing a finger over her mouth. Feras would surely allow Ismael to teach, even if he knew Ismael was a man, as Ismael was old with grey hair. I loved staring at his face. So calm. Lined, but happy. I would paint my face with lines as satisfied as those one day. Inshallah.
    After a while, we were trusted and allowed to order a taxi, and so every Sunday, at four, Souad and I left for the Mathaf. For me, to paint. To indulge in colour and form. To live. For Souad, well I think she liked to be a little free of Nabeel, for a few hours at least.
    ‘What do you mean, Souad? Why do we need to prove our attendance?’

During the first term, Ismael covered a general introduction to form, proportion, tone, and use of materials. When Souad progressed, so did I. Always ahead. Acrylics now and long-handled brushes.
    ‘You are showing great promise, Amal,’ said Ismael standing behind me, ‘but still too many details.’
    He stood now to my side. Close. Closer than he should be if he knew. I imagined mixing the colours for his silvered hair. My thoughts, uninvited, turned to painting him. He would be about my father’s age I guessed. I wondered if my father would have looked as wrinkled and grey as Ismael.
    ‘No details, light and shade are all you need.’ Ismael was a man of the book, an infidel. Feras would not want him to stand so near. But he is Mudaris, the teacher, old and wise; I must treat him differently. This would be my argument if it came to it. At the end of the sessions, Ismael would hang back to help me mix the colours I should have used. 
    ‘You are using acrylics now, so it’s easy, come, I will show you.’
    He held the top of my hand and directed the brush into the paints, picking up just the right amount to match the shade of a sap green leaf or a cast shadow of purple. I married Feras at fourteen, and no man has ever touched me since. Souad, ten years older, had been kind to me, helped me with those things of which I knew nothing of. It was just my hand. Only my hand. Uninvited. But, only my hand. A tender direction to the canvas for a contour line here, a daub of colour there. Sometimes a vigorous smear to an area to make it a darker tone but his grip, always so gentle.
    ‘See, Amal, light and shade are all. Create the illusion of shape. Simple, no?’
    I muffled ‘Shokran’ beneath my niqab, and Ismael squeezed my hand much as a father would. How I hoped my father would have.
    ‘M’asalama, Amal. I will see you next week, yes?’
    ‘Na’am, of course, M’asalama.’
Each week the array of still life objects presented a new challenge. Books, fruits, glass and metal combined in distorted reflective compositions testing us, pushing us to observe, to grow, to notice.
    The studio was L-shaped, and I would position myself at a long corner, away from the door, to reduce the chance that any late arriving male students would set up close to me. Souad had taken to always pitching her easel next to Khalid, a swarthy Syrian butcher whose hands were more suited to painting creosote fencing. I could always sense when Ismael was behind me. He would say nothing for a long while and then lean in, sotto voce, ‘Amal, what is this?’
    He was always right. I’d painted something that wasn’t there, wider, longer, thicker than reality. 
    ‘Take your time, Amal, and look, observe. Let questions percolate in your thoughts. You are creating an illusion, Amal. Light and shade, light and shade.’
    Each week, new questions, new challenges, subtle, nuanced colours conjured from raw primaries. Primitive. Raw. Energising. I lived for Sundays. I longed for colour. I dreamed and, in my dream, would be the masterpiece I would paint. Oils, artist quality, no pigment-poor student hues, carved and mixed with palette knives and applied to stretched linen canvas, prepared with sienna washes and framed with carved golden lime wood. There was always a figure, reclining, at peace. Still. Silent. Like the silence of a room where a corpse lays. A man, but who? My father? My son? My husband? I must improve, improve technique and give clarity to my dreams. My life was Mathaf.
    Why was Souad always next to Khalid? Why did Ismael leave his advice on my paintings until after everyone else's? Why did Souad laugh so loudly at Khalid’s jokes? She was bored too. Maybe.
    ‘Next week, Amal, we are ditching this market stall of misshapen vegetables and going to the park cafe for coffee. No argument, OK?’ Souad picked up the hem of her abaya, to reveal a glitzy pink Jimmy Choo training shoe, and swirled the black fabric left and right, in a poor impression of a dervish.
    Khalid was watching us. Underneath, Souad was always dressed for escape, never far from her Givenchy scarves and Moschino handbags; accessories after the facts. Feras always wanted me in abaya, hijab and niqab, even for our marital time.
    It was Souad who persuaded him. ‘I’ll be her chaperone, Feras. It will make her happy and relaxed.’
Perhaps Feras thought if I were relaxed and happy, children would come. There was time yet to wait until such things needed to be spoken about. So, we didn’t.
    ‘It’s a perfect ruse,’ said Souad, who had removed her headscarf and was only slowly readjusting it. ‘Each week we can add a green here, a red there and create a colourful camouflage to disguise our real fun.’ She spun on her Jimmy Choo and moved towards Khalid.
    Khalid lit a cigarette, raised his leg onto his chair to rest his elbow against his knee, and taking a long drag, blew a film of smoke over towards Souad. Like a gossamer curtain, the smoke enveloped Souad as it billowed around her. Ismael approached and stood between us.
    ‘Amal, tonight we will mix yellow ochre, white and cadmium red.’
    ‘That’s a funny colour for Avocados and lemons, Ismael.’
    I offered Ismael my hand, uninvited. We were silent, as we found a small space on the palette board. I watched the colours blend with our joint effort.
    ‘Next term we have a sitter.’
    ‘Sitter?’
    ‘A model, a flesh and blood person to paint.’
    The word, flesh, uninvited, made my arm stiffen.
    ‘Oils too for you, Amal. You are ready.’
    Oils. The final medium. Progress. My dream’s image, my masterpiece, would have a sharper focus now. Surely. I noticed my breathing, quickened in the way an excited child does when opening a present. I stared at the palette as the ochre robbed the cadmium of its vibrancy to form a sludge of brown, lightened in parts by spiral streaks of zinc white. The smoke from Khalid’s cigarette made me cough and feel heady.
    ‘Just a little blue,’ said Ismael, picking up the smallest smudge of ultramarine.
    He resumed the mixing, encasing my trembling hand in his fist, overcoming my arm’s stiffness, increasing the speed of the swirling. The paint, now a cool flesh tone, stood impasto over the lower half of the palette board. Flesh. Blood. Life.
    ‘See, easy. We make many shades of flesh next term, Inshallah.’
    I straightened my niqab and placed my dirty brushes into my art box. I took a brief look around the studio, at the empty easels, each with splattered blobs of paint on the floor beneath them, at the leaves lining the still-life fruit basket wilting under the spot-lamp. Souad had left just after Khalid, and I was alone with Ismael. To paint flesh. Imagine. This man should not be touching me; he should not be saying these things to me. Souad should not have her head uncovered in this place. She should not have left with a man, smoking and laughing about such base things. This is wrong. I should stop. Feras. Ten years married, no children. But life was here. I needed to be here. Colour. Oils. I need to go. I need.
    ‘I will wash the palette, Ismael, and then I must leave.’
    ‘No please, I will soak them with the rest. But yes, it is late, your husband will be waiting for you.’
    I moved to the door and noticed a smear of flesh coloured paint had caught my arm. I folded the cuff back into the sleeve of my blouse and left. I looked back to see if Ismael was watching.

It made sense to keep the same Abaya for the painting classes. The class had become familiar with each other, and some of the western women wore spattered painting smocks. Anyway, I did not need proofs. Feras asked to see my picture most weeks and mine were accomplished enough to suggest at least a few hours of effort. I was happy when Feras praised my paintings. In fact, whenever he passed any comment. I could learn from all critique, however ignorant. That’s what I thought in the beginning. 
    I wondered now whether Souad’s primitive line drawings, in primary colours, were an elaborate ruse to allow her to produce a similar picture each week easily. A signature ticket serving as proof of attendance. Souad had been married for fourteen years and still no children.
    ‘Ismael thinks I should enter my pictures for the open exhibition at the Mathaf.’
    ‘Who is this Ismael?’ Feras sucked hard on the Sheesha pipe, baring his teeth as he did so.
    ‘The same Ismael I tell you about each week, the artist.’
    ‘What does Souad think?’
    ‘Why should that matter?’
    ‘It matters to me. Souad is your chaperone. Are her pictures going to be entered?’ A thick plume of white smoke momentarily obscured Feras’ face, and I could not judge the mood of his question.
    ‘No.’
    ‘Why?’
    ‘They are not good enough.’ Feras put down the Sheesha pipe being careful to wind the pipe around the glass bowl. As the smoke cleared, I could see Feras’ index finger curling to summon me over.
    ‘Ha, that is good. I will tease Nabeel when he comes over. Come, sit on my knee.’
    I tried to judge his mood as I moved towards him. A Mars black or a violet tempest? Maybe a grey swirl of anger that would land, hard, but never across my face. Perhaps if he was aroused, he would lift my paint pocked abaya and crevice his fingers deep within me. That is what he liked. How could children come from such a place? Rouged, swollen. Defiled. As I sat down on the flaccid landscape of his thobe, my relief was interrupted by the odour of Sheesha smoke that hung about his stale breath. Mint and lemon, his favourite.
    ‘Why are you in these?’ He picked at the vermillion scabs on the hem of my abaya.
    ‘I have been painting. I wear the same abaya when I paint. It seems sensible.’
    ‘I don’t like it. Take your clothes off. There is no need; we are here alone.’ 
    I removed my hijab and veil and pulled up my abaya, slipping all the material over my head in one movement. In the momentary darkness, I felt his hands move over my breasts, kneading them, hard, as he had done so often, even before I had any development. It was as if he was always searching to find the right combination of pummelling to ignite my interest. Failing, he would move south and dig. Hard.
    ‘Where are you this month?’
    ‘It is my time.’
    ‘It is always your time, what is wrong with you?’ He pushed me off his lap and uncoiled the Sheesha pipe and resumed a long drag, creating plumes of white smoke that obscured him temporarily and allowed me to rearrange my tee-shirt and jeans. I picked up my abaya, hijab and veil and hugged them close in.
    ‘I am young, the blood visits at different times. It will change one day. One day children will come. Inshahlah.’
    ‘Inshahlah, one day I will take a second wife, like my brother-in-law.’
    ‘I have some houmous and baba ghanoush prepared with pita bread, soft dates and labneh yoghurt. Let us eat, and we can talk about my paintings, Habibi.’
    I left for the kitchen and tried to think about which of Feras’ brothers had taken a second wife. Sarmad? No, too young and had not yet taken a first wife anyway. Hamad was in his first year of marriage and living in Germany where such a thing is not allowed. Hussein? Yes, it must be, but he seemed so happy and had talked many times, with some heat in his argument, about how he would never take up such rights.
    I arranged the food onto a wooden board, added some grapes and dates, and contemplated their composition and how I might approach it for a painting. It was crazy how obsessed I was. Ismael, uninvited, would appear to me often. I could hear him,
    ‘Amal, you will paint a masterpiece one day. It is in you; I know these things. Paint. You must paint.’
    The colours of the food were too drab, save for the pomegranate seeds punctuating the lemon beige of the baba ghanoush. I decided to make a quick fattoush salad. That would do for colour. I sprinkled on the pita croutons and thought of Souad. Fattoush was her recipe. The sumac, a spicy burnt umber, was the key she said, with mint and lime zest. Faithful Souad. She had taught me so much. How to limit the pain. How to use my hands and tongue to minimise marital time. How to make fattoush. I would paint the fattoush after supper, as a tribute to her. Its cucumber greens, tomato reds and dried beige pita would be enough of a challenge for tonight. After supper, I would persuade Feras to let me enter my paintings in the Mathaf competition. I removed my tee-shirt and jeans and cloaked the abaya around me. I would allow him to spank me, finger-dig and pummel me. I made an extra bowl of fattoush to place in the fridge for the still life I would paint later. Cold still life. Souad. Souad? My hand gripped the vegetable knife and placed it on top of a plump tomato. Not brother. Brother-in-Law? Souad? The tomato, squashed and spilling its seed, scooted across the marble surface as it escaped the knife’s edge which came down smoothly into the flesh of my thumb. Blood. Stinging. The blood, vivid against the white, followed a veined marble track before randomly following another. Deviating. Changing direction. He had said brother-in-law, not brother. Souad, his only sister. I returned with the food and placed it onto the ottoman at his feet. He was asleep clutching the Sheesha pipe just as I was gripping the errant knife. Underneath my abaya, the blood flowed. Stinging. Hard. What would this mean for Souad? For my chaperone? For my painting? I sensed my dream fading, muted tones of a limited palette, blurred lines disappearing into a one-point perspective. I dropped the knife. I must persuade him.
    ‘Feras, wake now, I have food.’
    ‘What have you done to your hand?’
    ‘It is nothing, I cut it with this knife. It is clean.’ I picked up the knife from the floor.
    ‘Ha, it really is your blood time.’
    He seemed pleased with his feeble joke. I dipped a honey-tipped date into the labneh and as I sat on his lap uninvited, placed the sweet fruit to his lips. 
    ‘Well, your royal highness the joke is on you because I was wrong. My time is next week. The cut is a sign from Allah. Let us try, and I will paint the babies that will come to us in our dreams.’ This talk of babies I knew would please Feras. Poor Souad. My fury, a glossed crimson explosion of lips and tongue, remained silent as they embraced his. Uninvited.

Souad and I agreed to meet at the far-away cafe, so named as it sat at the furthest point in the park next to Mathaf. The heat of raw summer had passed, and the gentle gulf wind blew through my abaya. Cool. Happy. Tonight, we would be painting our first sitter. Head and neck portraiture. Oils. Feras had agreed my painting could be entered into the competition at the term’s end and, after more persuasion, agreed that I could continue and finish all of the oil paintings at home. I created a small studio from the utility room off the reception hall. My space. Safe. Thank you Feras, I am sure children will come, inshallah.
    I took up a seat at the edge of the coastline bar, under a large orange awning. Its complimentary colour to the Arabian blue of the gulf made the sea vivid. Alive.
    ‘Salaam Alaykum, Habibi.’ Two hands had been placed over my eyes from behind. The oud scent was strong but unmistakable. Souad.
    ‘Wayalaykum salaam, you are late.’
    ‘You have your sketch-book and pencils, what do you care?’
    Souad walked around to take up the adjacent seat. A lightweight Burberry scarf was loosely tied around her hair and flapped in the quickening breeze from the sea. Her Versace blouse, red with a purple sheen picked up the tints of Burberry tartan. Plain lamp-black slacks led to white Ferragamo shoes. She placed her matching bag onto the table and summoned the waiter. Her angular, pancaked face had a look of blank idiocy.
    ‘Two Mint-lemon, and don’t forget the sugar syrup.’
    ‘Souad, you look…’ The truth was she looked fabulous and, like the head of a pecking hen, hers made regular checks for onlookers while making fine adjustments to clothes and jewellery. I didn’t, couldn’t say anything for a long while. Souad stared into the distance of the Gulf bay. A Dhow docked and dropped off its western tourists. The waiter arrived with the drinks.
    ‘Where is your abaya, Souad? You can’t paint in those clothes.’ I stirred the flakes of green mint into the pale lemon cordial and imagined painting it. Size two brush daubed with Winsdor green into a Naples yellow. Easy.
    ‘I am meeting Khalid for coffee.’ Souad picked up her drink and leaned forward careful not to spill a drop onto her blouse.
    ‘What? But… What? When? You can’t …’ I stuttered to a stop as Souad raised her hand and placed a finger over her mouth.
    ‘I am meeting him tonight.’ She poured a drop of sugar syrup into her drink with a steady hand. ‘Amal, you will paint my picture and stain my abaya.’
    ‘I can’t. What will Nabeel, Feras… it’s not right.’
    ‘You are not the only one with crimson bruising and black eyes, my sister,’ said Souad, taking her hand and gripping my thigh. ‘I am abused, and I will not wait for my life to start. If it is to end, I will do this first.’
    ‘Souad, you are too dramatic, you should speak to Nabeel. Please don’t do this.’
    ‘Are you happy, Amal?’
    I took a long slurp of the minty-lemon cordial and tried to remember. I had not added the sugar syrup, and the bitterness made my nose and eyes scrunch together.
    ‘Yes, I am happy sometimes.’
    ‘When?’
    ‘When I paint. Please, Souad, don’t take this away from me.’
    ‘Yes, you are good, Amal. It won’t take you long to produce something for me.’
    ‘I should not be there alone, Souad. Please’
    ‘You have Ismael. He is like a father to you. I think he likes you too. Perhaps you should have coffee with him.’
    ‘Souad, that is not right. Please do not do this.’
    The waiter removed our empty glasses, and I ordered two coffees aware we only had a short time before the class started.
    ‘He will be here soon,’ said Souad. She paused until the waiter had gone, then swivelled around to face me, taking my hands in hers. ‘You must paint, and you must be happy Amal. I will never take that from you. Do this for me.’
    I withdrew my hands, immediately regretting it. ‘I heard about Nabeel’s decision.’
    ‘She is sixteen, Amal. She will give him babies.’
    ‘It is not too late for you, Souad, you are a young woman still.’
    Souad rose and checked her watch. In the distance by the car park, a light flashed. 
    ‘I must go. I will meet you outside the Mathaf at seven. You will paint my picture and stain my abaya?’
    I nodded. I felt lightheaded, my throat tight. The cool gulf wind cut into the sweat of my torso. I shivered as the waiter approached with the coffees.
    ‘Your friend, she has gone?’
    ‘Please leave the coffees. I am feeling cold and will drink both.’ 
    ‘Of course, Ma’am.’
    I placed two hundred Rials on the table. I rose to make my way to the Mathaf and noticed the stained coffee receipt flapping underneath the ashtray. I put it into my bag. It was proof we were here.

Each week Ismael would ask after Souad. I would explain she was ill, or her mother needed help, but that she would be coming soon. For the first half term, Souad would put in the occasional appearance too. Each week we would meet for coffee, and I would talk about some painting technique Ismael had taught me, new colour combinations, and she would tell me about the arrangements for the second marriage. Her name was Noor, and she came from a good family. Souad would move to a smaller neighbouring house and Nabeel would visit when Noor left to see her mother for two days a week as she was unwell and not expected to live long.
    ‘I love him, Amal.’
    ‘Of course, Souad. He is your husband, and he will care for you. It will work out for the best. I am sure. Noor, she sounds nice.’
    ‘Khalid, I love Khalid.’
    As the weeks went by, Souad’s attire was more relaxed. Faded jeans, Conway sneakers and plain white tee-shirts. The light flashed every week from the carpark. I learned it was his phone. Quaint subterfuge. She would leave for the car park and each week I would daub her abaya with small patches of paint, careful to match them with those used on her paintings. My paintings. Feras didn’t go back on his promise, and my studio grew in size and complexity. I converted a clothes horse into a small shelf to hold my paints and brushes. I would prepare Souad’s sham paintings ahead of the class as I wanted to maximise my time with Ismael.
    ‘This is a good likeness, Amal.’
    ‘Thank you, Ismael.’ He no longer enquired after Souad which meant I was more relaxed around him once more.
    ‘But too dark, and the tones have too much contrast. Here.’ He placed a large brush, loaded with a thin raw umber wash, into my hand and directed it to the painting. ‘See.’
    As we jointly swished the brush over the entire painting, as if by magic the face of the sitter took on a reality that had been missing.
    ‘It lightens the dark and softens the light tones. Gives you a mid-tone too where you had nothing. Clever, no?’
    ‘Mashallah, Ismael, I am impressed.’
    ‘No, my good friend, it is you who impress. I wish I could paint you. Do you think it is ever possible?’
    ‘Ismael, there is not enough black paint in your office to cover how I look.’
    ‘But I have crimson, yellow ochre and white.’
    I couldn’t speak. I picked up a signing brush and dipped into the Mars black. I scrawled Amal Haddad into the corner of the painting as usual except the writing wobbled on the horizontal.
    ‘Amal, here.’
    Ismael took my hand, and I readied myself for the usual instruction in tone, or paint mix, although I found it hard to remove the fine tremor that had set in my arm. But instead, Ismael picked up the canvas in his other hand and holding it outstretched paraded me around the studio.
    ‘My friends, behold. Amal Haddad will be representing us in the National Mathaf competition with this entry.’
    There was a round of applause, and kind comments as the class filed out. Ismael turned to me.
    ‘You are a beautiful painter, Amal Haddad. Excuse my clumsiness. I hope we can be friends. I would hate for you not to come here. I would like you to be my assistant. The class is getting bigger next year, and I think you would be perfect. I want to attract more Arabic talent and, well you would be a great asset. I am sure you understand why.’
    ‘I am not used to such honours, Ismael. I need to ask my husband, persuade him perhaps.’ As I spoke the scene in my dream appeared to me, uninvited. The reclining man was Feras; it must be my husband, Feras. Still, at peace. I could see all the colours needed, knew my approach and how I would start, finish and endure. Sharp delineation, vivid reality. Feras, accepting, agreeing and starring in my masterpiece. Ten years of barren marriage now struck with colour, with hope. I would tell Souad; I would persuade her to try again with Nabeel. Allah would bless her as he had blessed me.
    ‘Ismael, thank you. I have an idea for my next painting too.’
    ‘Win the competition, Amal, and you can put any painting forward as the Gulf’s entry for the International Abu Sana prize. Your Sister-in-Law will be very proud I’m sure.’
    Souad? Of course.  I rushed outside aware I had run late. So much to tell her. Where was she? Has she taken a taxi by herself? No, I had her abaya. I hadn’t stained it tonight. No Time. No matter. One week wouldn’t matter. I phoned her, and on the third ring, a man’s voice answered.
    ‘Khalid? Is that Khalid? I am waiting for Souad, is she with you. Tell her I have her Abaya.’
    ‘Amal?’
    The voice was unmistakably Nabeel’s. I hung up. What had I done? I would get home to Feras and say Souad left early. Felt unwell. Persuade him. I am his wife, the great painter, Amal Haddad. Mudarissa, Amal Haddad. Yes, I must, it is my duty. I imagined his hands touching me. Digging. His thin dried lips. Kissing. Touching. I must persuade him and make a start to paint him. The man of my dreams. Persuade. Tonight.

The house was quiet, and I could see in the distance that my studio was still intact. I listened. Silence. Pure and simple. A blank canvas of time and space. Still. I moved through the house like an intruder, uninvited. I righted the hallway consort table that was lying on its side and replaced the telephone. In the kitchen, scattered cutlery and broken dishes lay around the floor. The central light had lost some bulbs and was gently swinging casting a dim light. I used Souad’s abaya to wipe vermillion spots from the fridge door and searched for the side light switch. I threw Souad’s abaya to the ground and used my feet to mop up the sticky floor. What would the story be with Souad? How would she contact me? I couldn’t leave, I had to find Feras and make this right. I would paint him. He would like it and love me. Make love to me. Properly. A masterpiece. I would be allowed to paint, and I would be Amal Haddad, Master painter. I would be someone, and Allah would bless me with children. I would have children, and they would be safe. My children would have no bruises under their clothes, and they would marry for love and be loved. I had no idea if I was happy, but salty tears stung my cheeks as they evaporated in the dry heat of the kitchen. The silence developed a rhythm, a low rocking rhythm. In the corner, sobbing, a wild animal, curled, spent. Limbs wrapped around tightly hugged knees, doleful eyes flashing white with each swing of the ceiling light. Souad. In her hand she clutched a knife, a blunted meat cleaver, dripping a darkish bloody oil.
    ‘Souad, my darling.’ I rushed over to coax her out. ‘Are you hurt? Please give me the knife.’
    ‘My little Amal,’ said Souad as she took her abaya from me, ‘these are the stains of the devil.’ She began to laugh. ’The devil has stained this abaya, and soon the whole world will know its true colour.’
    ‘Souad, please come, stand. Let us move next door and sit. We will eat dates and yoghurt and drink coffee, and we will plan what we will say. You must forget Khalid, please.’
    Souad stood, draped her blood soaked abaya around her, and was persuaded to sit on a nearby breakfast stool. On her neck and hair streaks of blood, dripping onto her blouse joining other matted stains. Older stains.
    ‘It is over, Amal, you are free.’
    ‘Souad you are bleeding, please come to the bathroom let me wash you.’
    ‘I am not bleeding, but my kin is.’ Souad raised an arm and pointed to the Majalis. ‘Free, Amal. You will suffer no bruises, and you will have no idiot children, and I will see you in paradise, Habibi.’
    ‘Souad please do not talk like this. We will eat, and then you will sleep. I will persuade Feras, and he will speak to Nabeel. Please.’
    ‘Ma’salama, my little Amal. You will be fine. You must become a great painter and paint me from your memory. Name your daughter after me and have strong sons, inshallah.’
    The silence returned. I am alone. I must speak with Feras. I must persuade him. I moved into the main Majalis reception hall and spotted Feras’ foot at the end of the recliner. Stretched out. Still. Silent. This image was it, my vision. Exactly as I had dreamed it. Now was my chance to paint him. I left him, still and silent, and returned to fetch my easel. I laid out my colours, confident pinches of zinc white, burnt sienna, raw umber and yellow ochre. Canvas secured, I positioned the easel far enough away so that my aspect could place his whole body onto the canvas at a three-quartered recline. I could hear Ismael in my head, ‘No details, Amal, no details.’ I needed a red. Crimson to inject some life into his pallid lips, or cadmium to achieve a healthy flush to his bluish cheeks. My hand reached for the vermillion. I would need vermillion, a spicule of ultramarine blue and a dab of burnt umber. Thick, impasto, dripping vermillion. Blood for my masterpiece. No details, just shades of light and dark and in the grey tone of my thoughts would lie a truth. A masterpiece. Blood. I knew how to paint this. It was a strange thought to have, but like most thoughts, it arose without invitation.


&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">A Stroke of Blood The tree of liberty must be refreshed from time to time with the blood of tyrants - Thomas Jefferson</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twice upon a time</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/01/Twice-Upon-A-Ti.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twice upon a time" /><published>2021-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/01/Twice-Upon-A-Ti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/02/01/Twice-Upon-A-Ti.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
 &lt;blockquote&gt; Interesting, the idea that loneliness might be taking you towards an otherwise unreachable experience of reality&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Olivia Laing,The Lonely City&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;


Brothers, Sisters, Comrades, I feel I should start at the beginning, especially for my 19th and 20th Century readers. They’ll be plenty of time to explain later. Literally, all the time in the world. I’m getting ahead of myself. Having a time-machine, well a mechanism to travel in time, means I do that a lot. I have a dilemma and I need your help.
…..…………………Cut here ……………………………………………………….
    By the way, please feel free to cut along these perforations to rearrange the story. (This is a note for my 18th century readers in particular, who were, are and will be, fond of the periodical. Those of you post the Andromeda collision, who I have affectionately called the ‘Folders’, can mind-meld at your convenience of course using my public mindspace address: www.pms.mindmeld.public. Bear with me. Please. Just start wherever seems most comfortable.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    Cool, cold gold. Single, elemental, no alchemy will ever now convert me back to base earth. I’ll need your help with this later. To trade an eternity of immortal loneliness for a May fly’s intense community orgasm. I admit it gets confusing, even for me, and I’ve had an eternity to learn this stuff. Literally.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    I’m nine years old. Harrison Boulevard, Boise, Idaho. It’s quiet. The neighborhood that is. As long as I can remember I have dreamt of a golden angel. More of a golden shape really. It would whisper to me on the point of waking. Simple things at first, like ‘say ‘yes’ to the first question asked today,’ or ‘give mum a special hug.’ Nice things. Quirky things. I didn’t think it strange given what I’d heard Elders say in Church. But it was my secret all the same. Well, I told Grandpa once. He loved dreams and used to interpret them. Grandma read tea-leaves too. 
    ‘I see nothing but loneliness for you when you chase the gold, boy,’ Grandma would say at breakfast, especially when she’d had ‘one of her nights’, as they had euphemistically become known. She blamed me. Of course I knew later she was right. I’ll come to that. I don’t think they liked me having a special friend. Told me I was stupid. They saw it as a threat, I think. Well not think. I’ll stop all this thinking now. I know they did. You see its complicated and I might have to cut along another perforation soon myself. Suffice to say, I was the angel. Well, the future me. The educated me. The me that Grandpa tried to mold differently. ‘Chuck them books away boy, let’s you and me smoke a while and go fishin. Be kinda normal.’ Have I explained the whispering yet? Let’s cut to that now.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    1948. Grandpa, he’d been my first ‘whispee’. That’s the term I use for those I whisper to. I must have fried his brain.  He knew before I did what I was to become, because I had told him both before and after I had become it. Sorry, cut here if you wish. I told you it was difficult; bear with me a little while longer. It was his death, what we physicists call his real pinch-point that troubled him. Killed his hope really. He decided not to avoid it in the end. Told me my time would come too. My pinch-point. You see he implored me to stop it. The whispering. To accept I had a pinch-point. These pinch-points, in timespace, are where parallel eigenvectors meet. I can go visit folk before and after them, at will, but the point of intersection is a constant – Whatever happens at a pinch-point happens, always. No getting away from it. No advice from me can avoid them - they have to happen - Grandpa always has to die. He hated that whisper. I’d better explain the whispers too.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    Whispering is the term I gave to when I slowed the time machine down and entered a metaphysical shared timespace with another consciousness. I guess I appeared as a Golden angel to them too. It meant I could tell folk what was going to happen, warn them, or not (look, I never promised to be good). I’m mistaken by some for a poltergeist, or the arch-angel Gabriel, and sometimes for indigestion by the secular minded. Especially by those in the 20th to 3200th Centuries. Pre-enlightenment guys were crazy - they just burned people for mentioning a whisper. I don’t bother with them much now. For the most part, I travelled back in time just to stop Grandpa teasing me. I know what you’re thinking. Really I do. How can I stop something I’ve already experienced? I know it’s hard, but it’s to do with quantum entanglement theory and allowing intersecting spirals of the timespace to share eigenvectors with their respective Eigen functions. I did say bear with me, and I know I’ve lost those of you in the 17th Century pre-enlightenment, but the rest of you hang in there and skip this bit if you need to. 
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    I promise it will all come together. Don’t forget the Folders, either… we are nearly at that part. Let’s go back to a bit after the beginning.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    With all the whispering to my younger self, I was shaping my mortal self into a studious well-behaved young man. Straight-A hero. I majored in Physics, got my degree and was awarded a scholarship to Oxford, England to start a PhD in Quantum Mechanical perturbation of solid-state field theory. I was considered a genius. I was. But it wasn’t really my work at all. I’d been guided by my golden angel. By my future self. Here’s the thing. Before we get into the difficult physics stuff, imagine you could revisit your younger self… advise and guide to make better choices… then imagine you could keep going back until every choice coalesced into a pathway that led you to precisely where you wanted to go. That’s what I did. I know what you are thinking (no, really I do). You’re thinking which of these guys is the real me? Well, when I had my younger self on the path I needed, we melded. It’s a timespace permanent entanglement. We became defined by a single Eigen function, a complex conjugate of Hermitian space. In short, kind of like a pinch-point but where you carry on living. I worked out how to place my entire neural network, the essence of me, into a golden circuitry.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    Anyhow my flesh, our flesh, was replaced with a pure infusion of molten gold. Our neural networks mapped and run through a meshwork of golden neurones and synapses controlled by our shared single Eigen function. Sounds dangerous. It is, was and will be again, but you see once the first light speed time-warp was done I could move the golden cone anywhere and to anytime, like ‘running around a fairground quantum wall’ ( all directions at the same time, it’s cool). I could revisit mistakes an infinite number of times to correct them. I had no body, no corporeal reality save the small golden conical lump of metal that held me, well my thoughts anyway. It got lonely for sure. Thirty-five million earth years, shaping, tweaking and refining … me, my thoughts and philosophy. The whispering was a lifesaver really, a way of meeting people, of remembering what I was giving up. My big mistake was not spending more time in the future. Evolution of the human form was so subtle. I didn’t see it until it was too late. I was out of that loop. Like a headless chicken, traveling through time as a golden circuit, not evolving like all around me. More of that later. Later. Perhaps I mean before. Time. It gets complicated but we are making a good start. Bear with me 
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    During my PhD the angel whispered in my ear almost continuously. Einstein, Bohr, Bose, I consulted them all. You see to build a time machine you have to approach the speed of light. No way round it. The thing is once you get there you become fat. Really fat. Well, infinitely dense is how Einstein politely put it. No way round it. No point trying. Except, Heisnenberg chipped in one fateful day with his uncertainty principle and I think we all saw the light (excuse the pun, it was a favorite of Plank’s when I went back to explain it to him. ‘I know Gustav, if we travel at the speed of light all is black, but its a pun. Lighten up a little’). You see you can’t know the speed of something and where it is, infinitely precisely. There’s always a measurable uncertainty. That’s when the penny dropped. Don’t travel in a straight line. Spin. I postulated that spinning at increasing speeds with auto-gyroscopic balance using the increasing density to first propel one side and then flit to the other would mean as the velocity of light was reached the infinite density would act to complete the final push to reach the speed of light. Like a perpetual motion machine but using the properties of a single element, gold, to avoid the inter-elemental friction that would normally build to slow it down. Put the whole thing in a big magnet and the spinning becomes something you can control. Steer. 
    However, once we had a spinning cone of solid metal spinning at the speed of light, with my neural networked consciousness mapped, we lost it. Infinitely dense you see. Fell right through to middle earth. Slowed down and lightened but it was miles down by then. The next phase in space meant it wouldn’t bump into anything. ……… jump back a little now…. It’s beginning to make sense I hope you agree….  Once we had cracked the neural network and replacement of the flesh by gold we had our time machine. The device would float in space but its spinning speed meant it could travel into any timespace continuum; surf the wormholes in other words, and in other worlds. My neural network could plug into any system of information technology architecture, which meant I could speak to anyone, look at anything from any time period. Whisper. Immortal. Floating through space. I kept copies of myself in all the common timespace zones for backup. Multiple consciousnesses. Cool, I thought, until I met the Folders.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    After a few million years I grew bored. I felt useless. What’s the point of being immortal if you can’t use your knowledge to save mankind? The Andromeda galaxy was coming to destroy our solar system. It has been visible to the naked eye since the 9th Century…. Man, it got real scary in AD 3,003,444 - new planets as big as the moon everywhere in the night-sky. That’s when I decided to save the world. Travel to the pre-Andromeda timespace and help them to escape.
    That’s when I met the Folders, humans who had evolved over the four-billion years since my golden Bar Mitzvah. Never saw them coming. Felt like a total idiot. I was technically. You see humans became aware of the basis of consciousness in AD 2,998,504 and the subsequent expansion of philosophy became so advanced that human brains finally understood the truth of everything, scientific and numinous. Their bodies had changed too. Beyond recognition. It happened about a billion years before Andromeda collides and destroys both galaxies - plenty of time for the Folders to escape and they knew it. Their bodies had evolved to a new species line, so that their brains were now evenly distributed over an entire paper-thin skeletal structure that could fold in and on itself. Not just supple backs and bendy joints, I mean fold and fold again into an infinite origami of translucent flesh. They began to fold into each other. The entirety of Earth’s population folded into each other, thousands, millions, billions orgiastically packed into tiny spaces and launched to escape the solar system. The supernatural was long dead. The secular had evolved but my brain was fixed, inorganic - I had eternal life, of sorts, but not the means to understand the new philosophy - when I whispered to the future folded brain they were beyond my reach - they simply didn’t need to believe me – Occam’s razor cut me loose to cycle a personal time-loop of finite choices, always repeating and never changing in scope or desire or differentness - for many I whispered to I satisfied their first cause - that which existed before anything - but the Folders had outgrown me - natural selection had weeded my usual followers out and I became a mere observer of this future folded race. They were successful too. After Andromeda and the Milky way had settled their score, the universe’s other galaxies teemed with life evolved from the Folders, whose bodies continued to denude themselves of substance whilst their brains became ever more complex and delicate - the folds merging into one, the individual becoming the community, a perfect multi-mind meld. Offspring were like mycelial buds just appearing between convoluted neurons wrapped in a cling film skin. Death became irrelevant as the whole mass shared a single consciousness. The singularity of an individual became meaningless. In a way, I was there before them, billions of years before when I gave up my body for a golden concretion. But I’ve become irrelevant. It’s the risk I took I guess - too advanced for my old whispered audience and not able to penetrate the awareness of the folded people of the future - But you dear reader are my consolation, I sense an empathy for my plight. I face a pinch-point, my final pinch-point. I won’t be able to come back and whisper to you. What do I do? Cut here or read on, I’ll leave my fate to you. I’m tired.
…..…………………Cut here. ……………………………………………………….
    So, you’ve read on to the end, which is rapidly upon us both now. Wish me well. Think of me sometime. Remember me, brothers, sisters, comrades. Fraternity. Modernity, for ever and ever….. Eternity. It’s Hell. Amen. End of transmission.
* * *

* * *

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">Interesting, the idea that loneliness might be taking you towards an otherwise unreachable experience of reality Olivia Laing,The Lonely City</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Angelo</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/31/angelo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Angelo" /><published>2021-01-31T01:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-31T01:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/31/angelo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/31/angelo.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Angelo&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;A woman searching for love finds it in earth-shattering style&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angelo - a love story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Ah, when to the heart of man
Was it ever less than a treason
To go with the drift of things…’ Robert Frost&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;

Daphne Robins decided to end her life immediately. Not in the conventional way with bullets or paracetamol or dangling from a beam. Far too dramatic. It was more of a replacement she was looking for. She’d been drifting. She knew it, and a change was needed. Not a small, measly, January-the-first-gym joining change, that wouldn’t do at all. She needed a profound, wow-your-so-brave-I-never-thought-you-would-could-facebook-status-update-to-all change. 
    Cathy, at work told her to loosen up, to stop watching from the sides. Office Christmas party and Cathy was pissed, but there is often profundity in the gin-soaked tongue; she didn’t want to be that woman anymore. She snuck a glance at herself in the hallway mirror. Terrified. A cold shiver wrapped her neck. She shut her eyes and moved towards the mirror, placing her head against its coolness. Pulling back, she opened her eyes and lingered on an image not recognised for years. Recently, everywhere, in all the places that were her world, she’d felt the casual brutality the young display towards the old. How vulgar you are Daphne, hankering after youth, how vain, how selfish. How irresistible. Here she stood, woman, a dauber of paints, blushers and mascara. Why?
    ‘I’ll tell you why Daphne Robins,’ her nose pressed to the mirror now so that her eyes searched the blur for her soul, ‘because winter is eternal and because if you don’t the east wind will be at your throat all the sooner.’ Her mascara moistened. It was overdone and made an almost perfect oval with the dark bags under her eyes. Her large looped silver earrings injected a sense of drama that her features lacked. 
    In years to come, friends would discuss how Daphne Robins came to be in Mexico, and swap theories about secret lovers, undiscovered crimes. She wouldn’t be there to tell them, of course, but they would have been as surprised as Daphne at the speed with what followed.
    I’ll treat it as a project, she thought, outlining the big steps in her head, as she returned to the bedroom to get her diary and write out some detail.
    She would have to pack, of course, and tell work she wasn’t coming in. Never coming back? She felt energized by the decision; her heart beat faster and more forcefully in her chest, as she poured the contents of her dressing table drawers onto the bed. She was making a start. She was doing stuff. This was real now. Gray nylon slips and white (always white) M&amp;S bras and firm control full brief knickers filled the bed. She reached for her grey Samsonite suitcase above the wardrobe, last used for a girls’ weekend in Benidorm. Her friend, Suzie, had tied a pink ribbon to the handle so it could be recognised on the baggage belt. She wiped off the dust and eased the zipper carefully and opened the case onto the bed. Inside, a small pink ‘Victoria’s Secret’ box. She took out a lace-logo thong, pink, black silk edging, with tiny embroidered lettering, ‘sexy’, over a two-finger width gusset. Suzie had bought one for all the girls. Daphne wouldn’t wear it, said she’d like to keep it for a special occasion when she got back. She couldn’t even remember the names of the other girls now. They’d sung ‘Angelo’, it was number one, she remembered that.

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long ago,
High on a mountain in Mexico
Lived a young shepherd boy, Angelo
Who met a young girl and he loved her so

Running away together,
Running away forever,
Angelo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

1977. Forty years. She ran a finger over gusset. Sexy.
    ‘Genie of the box, grant me three wishes.’
She waited to laugh at her joke, but instead tears arrived. Tears for the 18-year old Daphne. The Daphne who waited for men who liked the poetry of Robert Frost, the Daphne who wouldn’t wear a thong, the Daphne who wondered if life could be enjoyed only in the limbs of youth. She stripped, carefully hooked the thong through both feet and attempted to pull it up. Whether it was the age of the material, the width of her thighs, the speed with which she was keen to cover her nakedness, it didn’t matter now. The thong ripped and fell to the ground. Her nakedness shamed her. An indelible truth, deep at her core, surfaced. She must go, go now, not waste another second.

&lt;em&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Running away together,
Running away forever,
Angelo&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/em&gt;

She replaced the tattered material into its box, placed it in her case, along with a several pairs of plain pants in case she lost her nerve to buy a replacement. What would people think if she had an accident in those anyway? She imagined the stern face of the mortician, tutting and shaking his head masterly head at her body, on the slab, and dictating like they do on Prime Suspect,
“Here we have the obese body of a 58-year old woman, Caucasian, little in the way of expected track marks or tattoos given the wanton logo-laced thong covering, well covering not a lot…’ 

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lived a young shepherd boy, Angelo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; 

Mexico. In large letters, now underlined, at the top of her fresh blank diary page. Good as anywhere to start over she thought. She wasn’t looking for a shepherd boy though. She liked rugged men. Men’s men. Fireman, broad shouldered, with stubble on their chin. Not like the men at the office. She imagined being carried over the shoulder of the shepherd boy, now grown fire captain, Angelo, her Angelo, with her thong-covered arse, bare to the sky, holding on to his leather chapped trousers for balance.

&lt;em&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Running away together,
Angelo…&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/em&gt;

    She was good at projects. She’d told her parents she was a project manager for ‘Decor homes.’ The good thing about old people is they don’t check facts. No detail required.
    She was really an office administrator for a door furniture store. It wasn’t ‘Decor homes’ either, but ‘Knobs-R-Us.’ The irony wasn’t lost on Daphne. Every year, new apprentices would be sent to the office with some variation of asking the girls whether they’d like the small, or big knob catalogue. The other girls laughed, but Daphne had died a little each year.
    She rehearsed the call into work. More than a husky voice was needed, as that would only buy a few days. D&amp;V the same, but at least that would keep people away. No, she needed something serious; something that would take her out for a few weeks and make sure people didn’t visit. The lying came easily to her. Not that she was practiced. More that she had never lied before about anything serious and knew she could cash in on that reputation.
    ‘Hi, I won’t be in today …well for a while actually... probably…can’t say much, saw the doctor yesterday, small op needed… I’m going to my sister’s place in Grimsby… to recuperate.’
    The tattered thong was soon joined by three pairs of slacks, four blouses (wing tipped collar, satin sheen effect, size 18 white, always white), flat bottomed brogue effect shoes, and her favourite comfort down toweling set, ( just the bath robe, for space, she thought best.) Hair straighteners, dryer, toilet bag and cosmetics completed the pack. She placed the case by the front door, briefly admired its symbolism, headed to the study and fired up her PC. Click. 10:35 pm flight arriving at 05:00, Mexico City, the next day. Things always looked fresh at 05:00. New start. It felt right. Click. She wondered if the days would really ever be new again, rather than just following each other, like the arms of a Quixotic windmill, rising, falling, to rise again. And to what purpose? New days, new dawns. She had to believe, she had to have faith. 
    Click. Fourteen nights at the Hotel Stella Maris, three stars, not too ostentatious. She didn’t want to attract the wrong type of… Angelo. Click. Ocado delivery next for when she got back. ‘Mexican food’ in the search bar, brought up a range of tacos, quesadillas, enchiladas, fajitas, black beans, nachos, and el paso dips. She imagined her burly Angelo tucking in, as she served him in a pink, (now always pink), skimpy thong. A new one. Fiery red jalapeño logos. She imagined lying on his thick, matted chest, her hands exploring him, licking guacamole from his erect nipples.
    At checkout, the order was short, by twenty pounds, to qualify for free delivery. She added toilet duck, room freshener, thin bleach and some rich tea biscuits. Still ten pounds to go, she wondered what sort of things a man, a man like Angelo, any man, would really like. She settled for Yorkie bars (pack of 10), a variety of assorted real ales (4-pack), and … a small tub of guacamole. Click.
    She wasn’t to know that the unopened bags lying in the porch would prompt a call to the Police. That, and the fact that she had no sister in Grimsby. 


Daphne had seen the sign at check in, and signed up immediately.
Singles Night, Stella Maris - Join us for a night of Mariachi folk music.
    She spent the morning shopping at the swanky Centro Santé Fe mall. At lunch, she ordered two cocktails (tequila with a grapefruit-soda served on the rocks with a lime wedge) and spent an hour choosing which lingerie shop she would visit. She wanted a quiet-no-fuss-no-chat assistant, preferably wearing headphones, distracted, I’ll-take-your-money-don’t-care-what-you-bought type. Fiorentina. 2pm. Quiet, as planned. She was met by the dead stare of three manikins, dressed in flimsy Oxford blue lace-lingerie. She felt sorry for them, stuck there all day, gawped at. She picked up the promotional packaging, carefully arranged at the manikins’ feet, and was pleasantly surprised to find a size 16. Head down to the till, pin code, bag, a mumbled ‘gracias’ and out. Job done.
        Singles night was to start in the Galleon bar. She had just enough time to shower, shave her legs and slink into her new purchases. She picked up her free La Cucaracha hat from reception, the symbol of the singleton for the evening, and headed to the ship-themed bar. As she walked, she felt the soft satin slip easily against the fabric of her black dress, and felt sexy, confident. Perhaps. At a large oak effect table, signposted ‘Captain’s mates,’ she joined a group of three girls and two men. Conversation was simple, strained, and competed with the noise of faux timbers creaking, of plastic masts swaying, of nylon ropes whipping in a strong breeze against the paper canvas of the good ship, ‘Armada.’ There was laughter all around them, the hubbub of real conversation, knowing conversations, crescendo and diminuendo conversations, the melody and cadences of real couples. No lifejackets here, thought Daphne, as she looked for a lifeboat. Hang on stowaway, hang on girl.
    It was the screams she heard first, screams that carried on the wind, followed by smoke and grit, and swirling vortices of rubble. One of the group fell at Daphne’s feet and as Daphne stooped to assist, she noticed most of the girl’s head was missing. Daphne threw herself under the table and tried to brace herself against the violent shaking and lumpish concrete that now fell like confetti from the four-floors above.


The days that followed carved no variation in the blackness that surrounded Daphne. When she was conscious she tried to feel her body by twitching areas in sequence from her feet. Her left arm was stretched ahead of her, stuck, with a little movement in her fingers. Her tongue fixed to the roof of her mouth, dry as parchment paper, and her breath, shallow, constrained by slabs of concrete. There were others near her. The dead. The crushed. Those, like her, waiting, twitching, dying. She was unique, but the same. The dilemma of being human.

&lt;em&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Hiding from every stranger
Angelo&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/em&gt;

    ‘Here! Under the slab. A Woman’
    A brilliant shard of light pierced Daphne’s left eye. She felt warmth in her left hand, a grinding pain in her arm, a vibratory low rumble of male voices, a noise, the scurrying of what sounded like animal paws, clawing, digging. Now, more clearly, she heard,
    ‘Here! Under the slab. A Woman’
    A rough pipe threaded through the dark space. Water. Fresh air. Hands touching her, grabbing her, caressing her. She gulped at a small rivulet of water that formed at the corner of her mouth. Daylight focused itself around a hand. Her hand, it was her hand, held by another. A strong hand, a calloused hand, a hand that had been digging for days, searching for her, restless, undaunted, fighting…for her.
    ‘Angel…?’ Her voice trailed off into the infinite space that now surrounded her. Lifted, floating, blinded by whitened Mexican sky, floating higher, higher in rarefied air. Her hand felt the firmness and gentle caress of him, and she strained to make out faint whispers from the blackness deep within and below,
    ‘…away… together … Angelo…’
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">Angelo A woman searching for love finds it in earth-shattering style Angelo - a love story Ah, when to the heart of man Was it ever less than a treason To go with the drift of things…’ Robert Frost</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Certifiable Love</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/30/certifiable-lo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Certifiable Love" /><published>2021-01-30T20:48:36+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-30T20:48:36+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/30/certifiable-lo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/30/certifiable-lo.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Certifiable Love&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;preconnect&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.gstatic.com&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link
      href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Montserrat:wght@300&amp;amp;family=Roboto+Slab&amp;amp;display=swap&quot;
      rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt; An inspiring life coach, a grateful student - a story of obsession and its deadly consequences&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;section&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;Certifiable Love&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;
        white-space: pre-wrap;
        background-color: rgb(226, 223, 223);
        color: rgb(7, 6, 6);
        font-size: 1.3em;
        font-family: Roboto;
        font-weight: 400;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 800px;
        line-height: 1.8em;
        border: lightgrey 1px solid;
        margin: 0 auto;
        padding: 2em;&quot;&gt;


‘Mr Gilmour, don’t push. Wait your turn like the rest of us.’
    Typical, so much fuss over a little prod. She had scrunched up her nose too, so that her eyes were narrow slits. She was Marion, I think, or Marlene or some such tartish equivalent, but I preferred Fat Rat. I had nicknames for them all of course. We were waiting for our end of course certificates, and Taylor had asked us to form a queue. Ignoring her, I maintained my concentration on calculating when I would be at the front of the queue. Nine to go. I imagined how Taylor would be with me. He’d have to be careful in front of all these people, I knew that. Perhaps, a whispered “well done” or a firm handshake that lingered just enough to pass an understanding. Eight. There was much that had passed unsaid between us over the last three months. I could feel it. Seven. I noticed a faded poster on the library wall. Its corner flapped in a strong down-draught from the cracked skylight overhead. Self-exploration and discovery - A twelve-week life coaching course by Taylor Houston. Six. Five. It had attracted an odd collection of students, which I guess was to be expected. Women with a taste for cheap perfume, pinot grigio and saturated fats. Flatulent baggy-arsed men who thought a catchy cliché could remove the odour of their intense sadness. Thank God for me. He couldn’t say that, but I could. Four. But he thought it, surely. Three. 
    I closed my eyes in preparation and thought of Taylor’s blond fringe, the way it flopped forward when he got animated in his lectures. He would sweep it back and often hold it in place until he finished his point. His tanned face always set in a natural looking smile and he moved with an easy casual elegance, like a well rehearsed dancer stretching out, comfortable in his skin. Taylor would be pleased with that observation, I thought. I recorded it in my notebook and decided I would share it with him. There was so much I wanted to share with him and thank him for. Two, Fat Rat was using every pathetic trick in her rodent vocabulary. I prodded. Taylor shook hands and passed her certificates over. I gripped the inside of my trouser pocket to keep my hand dry, aware that this would be the first time our hands might touch.
    Fat Rat took her certificate and led Taylor to the other side of the room. They were laughing at something she had said that I couldn’t quite hear. Selfish bitch. He gave her a hug and rubbed her low back as they walked towards the library door.  I picked up my certificate and waited. I noticed its border had faded towards the bottom.
    ‘Taylor,’ I said, projecting my voice across the room, ‘I think your printer is running out of ink.’  I felt my face flush as he approached. He reached out his hands to me. His arms looked so strong, so safe. I held out the certificate for his inspection and he took it from me. I had missed my handshake and regretted picking it up early.
    ‘Yeah I see, it’s all streaked. Sorry, my friend,’ he said, stroking me on the arm. ‘Look, If you’re bothered, I’ll drop one round later.’
    ‘Tonight?’  I said. ‘Yes...’ my dry lips stuck trying to form the word please.  The word friend reverberated in my head and made me feel dizzy. I concentrated on not fainting. I had often wondered if Taylor would ever visit my flat. I imagined us drinking Martinis and laughing about Fat Rat, learning to become closer friends.
    ‘OK I’ll pop it in on my way out tonight. You’re in those flats on Stonehart Avenue, yeah?’
     I could still feel the warmth through my shirt where he had touched me. I just stared right back at him.
    ‘Hey what’s with the Fifth Amendment? Don’t go all Tony “Big Man” Soprano on me now,’ said Taylor, faking an Italian accent, as he pretended to adjust an oversize invisible jacket. It was his favourite impression, Tony Soprano. I had bought a boxed DVD set of the Soprano series shortly after he had told us. I watched the entire series, five times. 
    ‘Capiche?’ said Taylor. He pushed the certificate into my hand and I felt his fingers lightly flick over my palm.
    Taylor’s wife, Holly, was standing in the doorway. She often arrived at the end of a teaching session to drive him home. I didn’t like her. She had a pinched face as if she constantly smelt something rancid. 
    ‘Taylor, would you like to go out for a drink?’ I shuffled my feet. ‘Perhaps this evening? I know an Italian place...’ I kept my gaze on the certificate in my hand. The words felt unreal. But I had said them as planned. I wanted to say them again and again, softly under my breath, so that Holly couldn’t hear them. Bitch.
    ‘Look at me, Chris,’ said Taylor.
    I couldn’t. I imagined his smile had gone, and I started to feel my legs weaken.
    ‘Maybe just a drink when you pop over with the certificate?’ I wasn’t sure I had made myself loud enough for Taylor to hear. Holly walked over, her stiletto heels like the sound of a high-pitched metronome.
    ‘I’m out with Holly tonight, Chris.’
    ‘Hi ya,’ said Holly.
    I looked up and saw her looking at my certificate, tilting her head to read it.
    ‘Hi ya, Chris Gilmour.’ She peered into her compact mirror, teetered on her heels, and took Taylor’s arm to steady herself. She adjusted her skin tight leggings, pulling them up with one hand, so that every detail of her gusset was displayed. She reminded me of the whores on Delaware Road. Whore. That was her nickname.
    ‘What you guys talking about then?’
    I had lost my chance. Bitch. Whore. ‘A stranger is a friend waiting for that first hello,’ Taylor would say at the end of each session. There it was, that word, ‘friend,’ again. He had said it too many times for it not to mean something to him. To us. 
    ‘Not much love. Look Chris’s certificate got all messed up,’ said Taylor. He placed an arm around Holly’s shoulder, and squeezed her into his side. This caused her breasts to bulge out of her leopard print top. ‘I’m going to drop another one round later.’
    ‘Ah, shame, you’ve all worked hard I ‘spect, Mr…’ Holly tilted her head at the certificate again, ‘Gimmor.’ Holly opened her compact, and applied a powder puff to her cheeks, as if the effort of talking must have deranged features she had checked only two minutes before.
‘Gilmore. It’s Gilmore.’ If the course had taught me anything this was the moment I had to bring it together. I wasn’t just any guy on the course. How could she lump me in with Fat Rat and the rest, it was preposterous. I looked down at the certificate and remembered a quote from week nine. ‘Tomorrow is the day you enjoy what you did right today.’ 
    ‘So about the drink?’ I turned and stepped to Taylor’s other side. ‘Will you come?’
    ‘Like I said Chris, not for now.’ He gripped Holly’s arm and led her to the door. As he opened the door he turned to face me. ‘I’m sorry about the certificate. I’ll get it all sorted tonight, I promise,’ said Taylor.
        ‘Of course, received, understood and certificated.’ I held the certificate aloft, and gave it a little shake. 
    Holly laughed and tottered down the front steps. They were gone. I felt foolish thinking this would be the time and place to put my plan of an evening out with Taylor into place. But he had said ‘not now’ and hadn’t said ‘no.’ Perhaps he was giving me clues, and I was too dumb to realise. I ran out to the foyer and saw them on the outside steps.
    ‘Taylor,’ I no longer knew how loud or soft my voice was, ‘please, a new certificate, you’ll drop it round? You promise?’
    ‘Sure man.’ He extended his thumb and index finger into a gun shape, and flicked his wrist. ‘Chow for now, keep to the plan man.’
    ‘Number nine, Stonehart Mansions, top floor,’ I said.
    He stooped and placed both arms around Holly’s waist, and kissed her. He raised his hand, and while still kissing, gave me a thumb up sign. She would need her compact again, I thought. He picked Holly up and threw her into the passenger seat of his Saab Convertible. I remembered his hug of Fat Rat. He seemed so masterful around women. He could fool any of them. 
    I withdrew to the silence of the empty foyer and let my breathing return to a normal rate. I ran my fingers around the edge of the certificate, and caressed the lettering of his name. I placed the certificate in my notebook and made an entry; ‘Ready to face life’s challenges, confirmed by Taylor Houston, (My friend).’ Of course it wasn’t going to be an ending. We had bonded. Taylor knew this, even if Holly didn’t.  I could see that it would be difficult for Taylor to talk freely in front of Holly, and felt buoyed he had given me a thumbs up. I hoped now I hadn’t been too pushy. She was the kind of woman who demanded attention, like a kitten, bristling with energy and excitement for shiny worthless baubles.  She had no interest in the deeper issues that I knew Taylor would yearn to discuss. That was something I could do for him. It was becoming clearer to me. I was just what he needed.  Tonight was my chance to prove it to him. 
##
I looked around the flat and tried to see it with a new eye, the eye of an important guest. On the polished oak floor of the main room, a two-seater leather buttoned Chesterfield and mahogany penny-table, took centre stage. The living area was open plan with no dividing wall between the hallway and the main room. It had been considered very avant-garde twenty years ago, and I had seen no reason to change it since. The floor timbers were old, and creaked like a ship when the wind’s up. I employed the use of a cleaner from time to time, a Ukranian girl. Her lack of English was useful in keeping conversation basic and functional. I was confident the toilet and bathroom would not attract any criticism from Taylor. The kitchen was clean too. I seldom cooked. The Ukranian had placed a bowl of pot-pourri on the penny table, which filled the room with a scent of lavender. I moved it into the bedroom, as tonight I would need the table for Martinis. The bedroom was untidy. I never allowed her to clean it.  I wondered now whether that was a mistake.
    ‘You look tired Taylor. We’ve had too many Martinis.’ I practiced the phrase into the small hallway mirror, imagining Taylor, tipsy, deliberating whether he should drive home. Yes, I could see that’s how the conversation might go and an offer to stay over could be a logical conclusion of the night’s events. I tidied the bedroom and then skipped into the kitchen to prepare the Martinis. 
    I had taken the flat, and shipped the Chesterfield and Penny-table from my father’s estate, after his death. I opened a window to air the room of the lingering lavender smell, and placed my Martini onto the Penny-table and sank back into the Chesterfield. A bare light bulb swung from a yellowed cord above my head, and cast a bright-refracted pattern from the Martini glass. It was mesmerising. Taylor and I would be sitting here soon talking, drinking ... becoming friends. 
    I remembered my Father entertaining friends. I would sneak down the stairs when I heard the deep mumbled voices of adult guests, and peer through the stair rods into the Drawing Room. I would catch a glimpse of him striding around larger than life, Gin in hand, laughing with a debonair air that gave no clue to his occasional lapses of temper. The same Chesterfield, centre stage in his Drawing Room, surrounded by wall to wall oak bookshelves brimming with books and papers. He looked so happy, so peaceful. Mother never visited the Drawing Room. After she died, Father kept the Drawing Room door shut, and I never again heard the hubbub of excited adults voices. I never visited the Drawing Room again either after Father died. He was found dead, by my aunt. She told me he had slipped and hit his head, which had accounted for the amount of blood found on the arm of the Chesterfield. Some stains are never removed. 
     I laid out my notes on the floor in front of the Chesterfield. There was another single armchair in front of a small television and DVD player I had purchased for watching the Sopranos series. I placed a small nest of occasional tables to the left of it, in case Taylor wanted a change of scene. I couldn’t decide on whether to leave the boxed set out. It would be useful I thought, in case conversation was difficult; an icebreaker. I decided to leave it on top of the television.  I placed the new glass ashtray on the arm of the Chesterfield, but hoped Taylor wouldn’t smoke. His choice, obviously.
    I felt a growing excitement and decided I would make myself another Martini. I placed my prepared questions on top of a single sheet of possible projects that I felt would fit in with some of the ideas Taylor had outlined in his course. ‘You’re the seed, I am the gardener, you will grow, just wait your turn.’ It was a lovely metaphor that Taylor always said with such gravitas, stressing each word in a slow precise way. My first question would be on the intriguing ‘Yesterday doesn’t count phrase.’ I often felt I was caught like a fly, in a spider’s web of yesterdays. Each gossamer sticky thread a memory from the past that held me, tied me down, unable to explore the future. 
    I had other questions too. ‘Decide, Done it, Do it, Good’, seemed wrong with respect to tenses and sequence. Surely ‘Do it’ should be before ‘Done it?’ So many questions to explore and a new certificate as well to look forward to. I fixed another Martini as a small celebration of my good fortune.
    I heard the pinging sound of the lift. Footsteps. This must be it. I downed the Martini and went through to the kitchen to make a start on two fresh ones. I left the door ajar wanting to avoid any awkwardness and thought it better Taylor enters and finds me casually making drinks in the kitchen. I waited until I could hear the characteristic creak from the central floorboard. That would mean Taylor was inside and would be perfect timing for me to enter with the drinks. I ran through my opening line, ‘Hi Taylor, Martini?’ I had practiced variations of opening lines but settled on this as it had a simplicity that I thought would suit the start of a relaxed evening. There was no creak. Instead I could hear what sounded like the postman fumbling with the strong spring of the front door’s letter box. The door swung back and slammed into the wall. 
    ‘Hey! That’s taken my nail off.’
    Holly was sitting in the doorway, sucking on her index finger.  I saw my certificate folded in half, guillotined by the letter box.
    ‘What are you doing here?’ I said. I placed the Martinis on the coffee table and walked over to look down the corridor for signs of Taylor. Holly looked up at me and stretched up both hands.
    ‘I slipped. The door was open, it swung back,’ said Holly.
    ‘Where’s Taylor?’ I tugged at the certificate stuck in the letterbox. It tore into two pieces. ‘You stupid ... look at my certificate?’ I screwed up the fragments and threw them down at Holly and then strode to the window, to see if Taylor was in the car.
    ‘Charming, thanks for nothing,’ said Holly. She struggled to her feet, smoothed down her ruffled skirt and searched her handbag. She pulled out her compact and used its small mirror to methodically check every square inch of her face.
    I felt lightheaded. I suspected the gin had started to take effect. I returned to the Martinis and took a large gulp. The alcohol felt cool at first, and then I felt its warmth spread through my chest.
    ‘Your door was open. It slammed back when I was posting ... that,’ said Holly pointing to the scrunched ball of paper I had thrown at her feet. ‘Taylor said you were keen to get it tonight.’ She laughed, and hid her face behind a cupped hand. ‘You know what I mean. A new certificate.’
    ‘Where is Taylor?’ I said. I used a slow deliberate tone, so that she couldn’t be in any confusion about the question. I took a swig of Taylor’s Martini, which kept the fire well stoked. ‘Well?’
    ‘In the car, outside. We’re going out to Domenicos. Thanks for helping me up’, said Holly. She was still peering at her compact and applying a tanned brush to her cheeks. She kicked the ball of paper, towards the fireplace. As she did her stiletto heel caught in a knothole of the floorboard. She stumbled and her left knee hit the floor hard.   ‘Ow…ow…ow… I think I’ve bust my knee. Help me up... please.’
    I laughed. Clown. Whore. Her face looked changed, sad, frightened as I approached.
    ‘You’ve pushed your heel through a knothole. It’s stuck. You’ll have to take it off,’ I said as I finished the Martini. I decided to fix two more. As I walked towards the kitchen, I heard a sobbing sound from the hunched Holly.
    ‘Where you going? Come back and take my arm, please, I can’t balance like this.’
    I returned with two fresh Martinis and placed them down on the television, near the window, and took another look up and down the street. Holly remained on the floor like a sprinter waiting for the starter gun, her right knee bent, right foot stuck firm with her left leg stretched out behind her. She now had her mobile in her hand. 
    ‘Stop crying woman,’ I said as I bent down to take the phone from her.  I was caught by a pungent smell of orange blossom perfume. Close up to her face I could see caked layers of foundation covering her pores, mascara heaped in thick rows on her eyelashes. Lips, blood red, glistening from the light of the bulb swinging above. Whore.
    I stepped over her right ankle and gripped her shoe. ‘Why did you fold my certificate, Holly?’ I snapped hard and broke off the heel from the body of the shoe. ‘Did Taylor tell you to do that, I don’t think so. I’ll need another one. Is that what you were ringing about?’
    ‘Do you know how much those cost? Look, get me up. Please, my knee is killing me.’
    I flicked open her phone and picked Taylor from the contact menu.
    ‘Hi Babes, you’ve been a long time, can’t you find it?’ said Taylor. A feeling of light-headedness intensified. He must be downstairs. He was coming after all. She must have tricked him, told him not to come. Bitch.
    ‘Hi Taylor, Martini?’ In the circumstances I thought it was a good performance and glad I had rehearsed it.
    ‘What, who is this? Is that you Mr Gilmour? Where’s Holly? Why have you got her phone?’ Said Taylor. 
    ‘Yes it’s… Chris. I’m expecting my certificate. You said you would drop it round. I have a Martini for you. Capiche?’ I felt eloquent, decisive; the fire inside was now a confident ember.
    ‘Put me onto Holly now. No wait, I’m coming up.’ The phone went dead. He was coming, this time, he was really coming. 
    Holly was now standing and trying to piece together her shoe. She looked like a child with a two-piece jigsaw, not able to figure it out. I laughed. ‘Taylor is coming, he’ll see what you’ve done,’ I said.
    ‘Are you mad? He said you were odd, said I should come and take a look. Never said you was this kooky. I’m gonna kill him,’ said Holly.
    ‘He wouldn’t say that. I’m a seed, I am going to grow, he’s my gardener.’ Holly started to laugh, her face looked like a grotesque gargoyle, her lips parting like a Cobra ready to spit its poison. ‘Tomorrow is the day you enjoy what you do today.’ I repeated Taylor’s mantra, getting comfort from each repetition. I wanted to drown out the words Holly was shouting. I was dizzy again. I could tell I was swaying. I reached for the Martini and downed it in one, then picked up the second. I wanted to be able to give it to Taylor. ‘Hi Taylor, Martini,’ I said as I moved over towards the sanctuary of the Chesterfield. ‘Hi Taylor Martini ... Hi Taylor Martini.’ I felt comforted by the words. I couldn’t tell when he would be here now, time had stopped.
    I couldn’t focus. A shape appeared at the door. I could hear a new voice. The room was spinning. I heard a clip clopping sound and realised Holly was limping over towards me. That orange smell again, I felt sick. It was so overpowering I could taste it. I spat to remove it.
    ‘What the… ? You just spat in my face. Taylor, he spat in my face, Taylor, Taylor,’ said Holly.
    She was screaming Taylor’s name in my face. This harlot who shouldn’t even be allowed to say his name, let alone touch him, kiss him.  I staggered back and reached behind to steady myself. My hand fell onto the glass ashtray. I gripped its sides and felt its cool surface. It felt like an anchor, a point of reference in the whirling blur of the room. It felt snug in my grip. ‘Decide, done it, do it, good. Decide, do it, done it, good.’
    ‘Hey Holly back off, I don’t think he’s well.’
    It was Taylor’s voice. Another anchor to focus on. He sounded annoyed with Holly.
    ‘He spat in my face. He’s spouting random crap too, ever since I got here. Look at my fucking shoe.’
    My view cleared a little. There he was, standing in the doorway. 
    ‘It’s not crap. Well, it’s the stuff I teach on the course. Decide, done it, do it, decide, good, you’ve heard all that before,’ said Taylor.
    ‘Decide done it, do it, good.’ I repeated Taylor’s words. Taylor was here, he was in my flat, we were talking. Decide, do it, done it, good.  Taylor’s own words in my own flat. The order mattered little now, tomorrow would be the day Taylor and I would enjoy the deeds of today. It was all so clear to me now, as if the cool glass in my hand had condensed the mist around me, clearing the hazy path that lay between Taylor and me.
    Holly was still too close, shouting too loud, her lips were still too red, too venomous. I brought the glass down on her head. She buckled like a stunned pig at an abattoir. Again, the ashtray slammed into her head. Blood spurted up and over the arm of the Chesterfield, dripping like a warm strawberry jam onto her face. She fell to the floor. I heard the creak of the central floorboard. Taylor was running towards me. He knocked me backwards, his body landing on top of me, shaking my arm until the ashtray fell to the ground. He held me down and I felt my face in the cool concavity of the leather buttons. His strong arms were pressing down on my chest, squeezing my breath out. I couldn’t speak, just a feeble whisper with my exhaling breath.  ‘Decided, done it ... you’re right ... its good.’ He was in my arms at last.

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">Certifiable Love An inspiring life coach, a grateful student - a story of obsession and its deadly consequences Certifiable Love</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech tips for writers</title><link href="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/30/tech-tips_writers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech tips for writers" /><published>2021-01-30T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-30T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/30/tech-tips_writers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://drmarkoconnor.github.io/2021/01/30/tech-tips_writers.html">&lt;p&gt;
  There's not much here yet on the tech front - however I plan on producing a
  series of short blogs to help writers in particular reflect on their workflow
  and how it can be assisted and hindered by IT.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I've been impressed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; and am using a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyller/jasper2&quot;
    &gt;free version of a Ghost-like layout&lt;/a
  &gt;
  for this site which is generated by
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on github for free.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://eastgate.com/Tinderbox/&quot;&gt;Tinderbox from Eastgate&lt;/a&gt; to
  organise my thinking and generate the site which I tweak with
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com&quot;&gt;VS-Code&lt;/a&gt; before a git push to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It's been fun and feels a little like the web of yester-year when everything
  was ad-free, collegiate and free! - there will be no ads here ever so please
  do subscribe to get the pearls of wisdom when they eventually fall from my
  increasingly sedentary pen.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dr Mark O'Connor</name></author><category term="tech" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">There's not much here yet on the tech front - however I plan on producing a series of short blogs to help writers in particular reflect on their workflow and how it can be assisted and hindered by IT.</summary></entry></feed>